<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JBake</title>
    <link>http://jbake.org</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jbake.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <description>JBake Bootstrap Template</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 11:09:33 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 11:09:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Bogota</title>
      <link>http://jbake.org/blog/2015/bogota.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/bogota.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/bogota_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attraction&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo Botero&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.banrepcultural.org/museo-botero&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.banrepcultural.org/museo-botero&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the items in this museum were donated by the famous Colombian artist Fernando Botero. This museum is for free and it also houses a numismatic museum. Botero has a very distinct style and you might find that he is obsessed with painting fat people. Botero said about his figures, “What I say is that they are not fat, but voluminous. If I make a fruit, a landscape, an animal, a man, anything, it is a deformation to exalt volume. So I do not see them as fat, but as voluminous. Fat can also be Michelangelo, Masaccio or all Florentine art that is voluminous.”&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Besides Boteros paintings and sculptures you can admire paintings from Picasso, Gustav Klimt, Max Ernst, Joan Miro, Salvador Dalí and many more. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/botero_horse.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Boteros Horse&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Botero Horse&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/botero_monalisa.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Botero Monalisa&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Boteros Monalisa&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/joan_miro.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Joan Miro&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Joan Miro&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo del oro (Museum of gold)&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is the biggest museum of gold in South America. It displays thousands of gold, silver and coper artifacts from the ancient indian history. Not only can you admire the artifacts but the exhibition tells a story on how the objects were made and how they were used in ceremonies and what spiritual role they played in the life of the ancient people.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can read about priests and shamans who identified them selfs with bats, evoked this animal habits in they own, they lived in dark temples, worked at night and flew when they were in transes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Yopo, a powerful hallucinogen that was extracted from the Anadenanthera tree, came from the Eastern Plains. It was inhaled using a small spoon or bird bone from trays with animals depicted on them that conjured up images of the transformations that were experienced.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The entry fee is only 3.000 COP (1 EUR)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/museo_del_oro.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Museo del oro&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Museo del oro - trays and bones for snorting&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Monserrate&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Monserrate is the hill above Candelaria and the city center. You can either access it by walking up the very steep steps (at least 60 min. hard climbing) or you can go for the easier option and take the cable car. The costs for the cable car is 8.500 COP (3 EUR) one way. You can return walking (30 min.). The return ticket is 17.000 COP (6 EUR). On the top of the hill are a monastery, small botanic garden and a market with hand crafted products and food. The view of the city is spectacular.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;National Museum&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is admission free and currently undergoing a reconstruction. Most of the descriptions and informations are written only in Spanish. However there is one remarkable exhibition room with marvelous paintings and projections which does not require any explanations. We have never before seen an exhibition room like this. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/national_museum.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;National Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;National Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Graffiti tour&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Meeting point is at Plaza de Periodistas at 10am or 2pm nearby the statue of Simon Bolivar. The tour takes around 2.5 hours and goes through La Candeleria district and finishes in downtown. Be prepared to hear tons of informations not only on the graffiti and the artists but also on social and economic issues of Bogota. Other then that you will get tips on restaurants, bars, alternative shops and galleries. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Street art in Bogota is nowadays well established and recognized by its citizens, landlords and shop owners. Street art is present everywhere but especially in Candelaria, where artists can even work by daylight in safe zones. Some landlords choose to commission international artists to avoid having their facade being tagged. Once the facade is covered with a piece, other artists respect it and they don&amp;#39;t paint over it. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will see pieces from Guecho, Rodez, Crisp, Likme, APC, Bastardia, DjLu,&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Even though the tour is free a tip of 20.000 - 30.000 COP (7 - 10 EUR) is appropriate.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art - La Candelaria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art - La Candelaria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art - Toxicomano&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art - Toxicomano&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Candelaria&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the historic center of Bogota. Some of the colonial houses are dating back 500 years. There are no two identical buildings. You will find many design shops, cheap hostels, restaurants and bars over there. Most of the historic monuments (Plaza Bolivar, Museo Botero, Monserrate ... ) are in walking distance.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Several universities are located in the Candelaria district. Many students and young people come to Plaza de Quevedo to enjoy street performances (mostly live music) and drinks (chicha, aquardiente or beer). This is definitely one of the best hot spots to meet with locals and have a drink.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We stayed in Casa Quevedo that is located at the Plaza de Quevedo and the party is right outside the door. Prices are around 50.000 COP (17 EUR) for a double room per night, breakfast included (eggs, bread, coffee). The 2nd floor has only two toilets which were not always clean.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Typical dishes from Bogota are Bandeja Paisa, which consists of meat, sausage, rice and beans and Aijaco, which is a soup with corn, yucca, potatoes and meat. If you are into sweats Columbia has a lot to offer. You can try pastry and cakes from tamarind, dulce de leche (caramelized condensed milk) and different types of fruit.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;When in Bogota try Chicha drink. It is fermented corn alcohol beverage, very sweet and sour. From Plaza Quevedo leads a narrow street in which every pub and bar serves this drink in a cup made out of totumo. Totumo is a typical plant for Colombia. Be warned that the portion is really big and not everyone likes the taste.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/food1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Aijaco Soup&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Aijaco Soup&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Dos Gatos y Simone&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is a cozy restaurant and the food is good. It is easy to miss, because it is all painted with graffiti from the outside. We chose estofado, which is meat with rice, some veggies, guacamole and salsa. The meat was tender and juicy, the sauce and the guacamole were nicely seasoned and tasty. One meal was with 20.000 COP (7 EUR) a bit pricey for Bogota.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Tao Calentao&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The biggest problem with this place is to find it. It&amp;#39;s hidden in small alley close to Universidad de Los Andes. Ask the students around they will point you in in the right direction. Calentao is a typical Colombian dish from rice, meat, beans and vegetables. You can select all ingredients yourself, or choose from one of the four versions on the menu (Argentinian, Thai, Mexican, Italian ). This is a bistro style and the food is prepared in front of you. Prices are reasonable and the portions are huge. We had troubles to finish our meals. We paid 28.000 COP (9.70 EUR) for two meals with lemonade.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Plaza de Mercado de Paloquemao&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The market is far from the center. Getting there on foot is possible, but don&amp;#39;t draw too much attention onto yourself as you are walking through some shady neighborhoods. It&amp;#39;s located on the corner of Carrera 28 and Calle 19 in front of a modern shopping center. The market offers a large selection of fruits, vegetables and herbs. Inside the market you will find several stands with authentic, home made cuisine. We had two soups, two main dishes (large portion of fried and barbecued chicken leg, lentils, platano and arepa) and lemonade. Altogether we paid only 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR). The portions were big and the locals were super friendly to us. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>http://jbake.org/blog/2015/berlin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/berlin.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;When one of our best friends moved to Berlin, we knew that sooner or later we will come to visit him. Andrea has never been to Berlin before. She loves techno music, art and good food, so for her Berlin was a must-do-trip. Berlin is incredibly cheap, provided you eat on the street, drink beer (not cocktails) and you stay in a hostel rather then a hotel. In that case you can experience Berlin on a budget. Berlin offers lot of fun activities and attractions. To visit all of the techno clubs in Berlin, would be our favorite choice. However, if you are not into electronic music, Berlin offers lot of exhibitions, galleries, museums, concerts and a free street art tour, which we highly recommend. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Free street art tour&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.visitberlin.de/en/see/museums-art/art&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.visitberlin.de/en/see/museums-art/art&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.exberliner.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.exberliner.com/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you like street art, join the alternative Berlin tour. Our guide Carl from Scotland who really loves this city and obviously knows a lot about the history and its underground subcultures. The tour started in the center, district Mitte. He showed us pieces from El Bocho, Sobre, Mr. Six and others. Then we moved on to the most &amp;quot;alternative&amp;quot; district, Kreuzberg. Since the tour we have looked at the city with different eyes, looking for art everywhere. We really appreciated that we were a small group about ten people and we didn&amp;#39;t disturb people around, because every time we kept distance. We also got tips about good restaurants and clubs where to go. This was a free tour and the three hours passed quickly, however we were very satisfied and left a tip and so did the rest of our group. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;East SiWee Gallery&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the longest open air gallery in the world with the most bitter history. That wall used to divide the city in two parts, the western and the eastern communist world. Many people died trying to cross it. Some of those who managed to flee had to leave rest of their families behind. It is the longest piece of the original Berlin wall with 101 murals from artists from all over the world and of course it is for free. It&amp;#39;s located in Mühlenstraße in Berlin Friedrichshain. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.eastsidegallery-berlin.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;East Side Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Techno clubs&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We have visited three clubs in two days, but you can go nonstop from Friday till Monday and there are so many of them that you won&amp;#39;t know what to choose. Of course you can use &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Residentadvisor&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; but even better is to ask the locals for the most recent hot spots, because some of them are very touristy and that&amp;#39;s not the best you can get. You can try to get to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.berghain.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Berghain&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, but count on a 2 hours queue and strong possibility that the bouncers wont let you in. Don&amp;#39;t go in large groups, and try to be of mixed gender, dressed preferably in dark clothes. Don&amp;#39;t draw too much attention on you, by speaking loudly or by being obviously drunk. Very popular and good techno clubs in the city are &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://aboutparty.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;://about blank&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.sisyphos-berlin.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sysiphos&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.kitkatclub.org/Home/Club/Index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Kitkat&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.water-gate.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Watergate&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We started on Saturday midnight in &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://tresorberlin.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tresor&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and we were a bit too early, because the club was almost empty. On the other hand it was easy and quick to get in because there was no queue. Tresor is totally worth to see! Its dark, very charismatic and industrial. The void audio sound systems on both stages rocks.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Later that night we moved on to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://griessmuehle.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Griessmuehle&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, which was probably one of our best techno events ever. We stayed only for three hours but it was a total blast. The club was hosting dj&amp;#39;s and producers from the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/lobster-theremin&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lobster Theremin&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; label. We are not sure if it was just because we were lucky to listen to such high quality techno music or if the club is organizing high class events like this every week. It was simply amazing. The interior and exterior is supporting this raw dirty techno atmosphere. There were no lights, no strobos on the main stage, just a bit of light from the bar which intensified the atmosphere. Be careful on the toilets which are the worst we have ever seen:) You can also chill out in the sun outside by the river.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Sunday night all major clubs play mostly minimal techno or housy music. Since we are not the biggest fans of that, we decided to go to the club R19, which turned out to be a mistake. Please don&amp;#39;t go there! Just if you like bad music, cyber techno or psytrance (I think it&amp;#39;s the same) and you can deal with weird people. Anyway it was an experience.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tresor&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/mixmag-1/imprint-100-lobster-theremin-label-mix-by-asquith&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lobster Theremin set&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.monsieurvuong.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Monsieur Vuong&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Alte Schoenhauser Str. 46&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Super fast service and good quality food. The food came five minutes after we have ordered. You can choose from a daily menu or order a la carte and the prices are more then reasonable, from 5-10 EUR. We ordered chicken with mango and minced meat rolls with noodles and fresh vegetables. Both dishes and the home made lemonade were super fresh. The Pho soup was ok, we have had better though. The service was efficient and nice. For two daily menu dishes, the pho soup and two home made lemonades we paid 33 EUR.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.curry36.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Curry 36&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Mehringdamm 36 und Bahnhof Zoologischer Garten&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;They claim that it is the best curry wurst in the city, The sauce was obviously home made and Andrea chose an organic sausage which was juicy and soft. For a middle sized sausage with fries we paid 3,50 EUR. Nice and cheap lunch. 10 meters from Curry 36 is probably one of the best places to eat kebab but prepare yourself to wait for at least 30 minutes, it is called Mustafa. We were standing by watching people getting their kebabs and they looked awesome, very fresh and in big sizes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.burgermeister.berlin/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Burgermeister&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Oberbaumstrasse 8&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;This is very nice and cheap fast food in the Kreuzberg district. I would appreciate a bigger portion of meat, but what can you ask for if you pay 4 EUR for a burger. The bun was delicious and obviously home made, the fries were also very good. Waiting in the queue, ordering and preparation time, all together it took max 20 minutes to get our food.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Burger from Burgermeister&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Burger from Burgermeister&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;What movies to watch and what to listen before (or while) you go&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Baader_Meinhof_Complex&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Baader Meinhof Complex (2008)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. is a 2008 German film by Uli Edel. Written and produced by Bernd Eichinger, it stars Moritz Bleibtreu, Martina Gedeck, and Johanna Wokalek. The film is based on the 1985 German best selling non-fiction book of the same name by Stefan Aust. It retells the story of the early years of the West German far-left militant group the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rote_Armee_Fraktion&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Rote Armee Fraktion&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (Red Army Faction, or RAF) from 1967 to 1977. The film was nominated for Best Foreign Language Film at the 81st Academy Awards. It was also nominated for the Golden Globe in the Best Foreign Language Film category.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Lives of Others&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (German: Das Leben der Anderen) is a 2006 German drama film, marking the feature film debut of filmmaker Florian Henckel von Donnersmarck, about the monitoring of East Berlin by agents of the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stasi&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stasi&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Germany&amp;quot;&amp;gt;GDR&amp;#39;s&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; secret police. It stars Ulrich Mühe (who died within a year of the film&amp;#39;s release) as Stasi Captain Gerd Wiesler, Ulrich Tukur as his superior Anton Grubitz, Sebastian Koch as the playwright Georg Dreyman, and Martina Gedeck as Dreyman&amp;#39;s lover, a prominent actress named Christa-Maria Sieland. The film was released in Germany on 23 March 2006. At the same time, the screenplay was published by Suhrkamp Verlag. The Lives of Others won the 2006 Academy Award for Best Foreign Language Film. The film had earlier won seven Deutscher Filmpreis awards—including those for best film, best director, best screenplay, best actor, and best supporting actor—after setting a new record with 11 nominations. It was nominated for Best Foreign Language Film at the 64th Golden Globe Awards.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Run_Lola_Run&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Run Lola Run&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (German: Lola rennt, literally &amp;quot;Lola runs&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Lola is running&amp;quot;) is a 1998 German thriller film written and directed by Tom Tykwer and starring Franka Potente as Lola and Moritz Bleibtreu as Manni. The story follows a woman who needs to obtain 100,000 Deutsche Mark in twenty minutes to save her boyfriend&amp;#39;s life. The film&amp;#39;s three scenarios are reminiscent of the 1981 Krzysztof Kieślowski film Blind Chance; following Kieślowski&amp;#39;s death.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Good Bye, Lenin![1] is a 2003 German tragicomedy film. Directed by Wolfgang Becker, the cast includes Daniel Brühl, Katrin Saß, Chulpan Khamatova, and Maria Simon. Most scenes were shot at the Karl-Marx-Allee in Berlin and around Plattenbauten near Alexanderplatz.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christiane_F._–_We_Children_from_Bahnhof_Zoo&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Christiane F. – Wir Kinder vom Bahnhof Zoo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is a 1981 German film directed by Ulrich Edel that portrays the drug scene in West Berlin in the 1970s, based on the non-fiction book of the same name written following tape recordings of teenage girl Christiane F. The movie immediately acquired cult status (which it still retains today) and features David Bowie as both himself and the soundtrack composer, which gave the movie a commercial boost. Both the movie and the book acquired cult status in Europe immediately after release, raising awareness of heroin addiction. The popularity of the movie was greatly boosted by David Bowie&amp;#39;s participation as both himself (portrayed giving a concert early in the movie) and as the main contributor to the soundtrack. Bowie&amp;#39;s music from his albums made in Berlin during 1976-77 is heavily featured throughout the picture, and as he was at the very peak of his popularity during the late 1970s-early 1980s, his presence helped boost the film&amp;#39;s commercial success.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/baader_meinhof_complex.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Baeder Meinhof Komplex&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/good_bye_lenin.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Baeder Meinhof Komplex&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ben Klock&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/benklock&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/benklock&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/ben-klock&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/ben-klock&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Rødhåd&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/rodhad&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/rodhad&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/rodhad&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/rodhad&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Marcel Dettman&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/marceldettmann&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/marceldettmann&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/marceldettmann&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/marceldettmann&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sven Vath&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/svenvath&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/svenvath&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/hightension1053/sven-vath-live-time-warp-2015-mannheim-germany-06-04-2015&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/hightension1053/sven-vath-live-time-warp-2015-mannheim-germany-06-04-2015&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Motor city drum ensemble&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/mcde&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/mcde&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/platform/motor-city-drum-ensemble-dekmantel&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/platform/motor-city-drum-ensemble-dekmantel&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Chris Liebing&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrisliebing&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrisliebing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/chris-liebing&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/chris-liebing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Pan Pot&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/pan-pot&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/pan-pot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/pan-pot&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/pan-pot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ostgut ton&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/record-label.aspx?id=803&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/record-label.aspx?id=803&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/ostgutton-official&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/ostgutton-official&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Cassy&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/cassy&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/cassy&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/cassy-official-1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/cassy-official-1&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

  </channel> 
</rss>
