<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JBake</title>
    <link>http://www.viabohemia.net</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.viabohemia.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <description>JBake Bootstrap Template</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 10:58:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 10:58:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Medellin</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/medellin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/medellin.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Party in Medellin never stops. We partied every second day till morning. It reminded me of my home city, Prague. We liked the city so much, that we considered the option to move to Medellin.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Paisas&amp;quot; (people from Medellin) are friendly and beautiful people. They will make you feel good in their city. They are aware that Medellin has the stigma of a violent city, controlled by drug cartels from the past, but they don&amp;#39;t like to talk about it. They even don&amp;#39;t want to say the name of Pablo Escobar. Instead our tour guide gave him the nick name Paul Broom, when she was addressing Pablo. It was like in Harry Potter with Lord Voldemort :) The city is now pretty safe and tourists are very welcome. The people of Medellin are happy to see the tourists that they even stop you on the street, shake your hand and ask where you are from. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On our second day, we have visited Parque Arvi, a large natural park on the top of a hill. It used to be a very dangerous place in the past, controlled by guerrillas. It is a getaway from the busy city for locals. That day was a vacation and the park was packed with children and young students. They approached us, gave us high five or told us hi. One girl asked me where I am from. So I answered, but she wasn&amp;#39;t really interested in the answer and she asked me with a smile &amp;quot;Selfie&amp;quot;? :) She wanted a picture with us.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Medellin is the second largest city of Colombia. Surrounded by mountains it was isolated from the world. In 1991, Medellin was the most violent city in the world. In 2013 Medellin was awarded as the most innovative city in the world. Certainly, the construction of the metro, universities and also libraries in the poorest parts of the city helped Medellin to fight the criminality. Nowadays there are still places where you don&amp;#39;t want to go after sunset, like the downtown, but this shouldn&amp;#39;t discourage you from visiting it during day time. Just use your common sense and trust your guts.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On the first picture below is a sculpture from Fernando Botero, the Bird. In 1995 somebody put a bomb into the Bird and more then thirty people lost their lives and 200 people were wounded. On the other picture is Plaza de Cisneros, what used to be one of the most dangerous places in the city. The city transformed this place by demolishing the old market and building white columns, which shine in the night and a library.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Transport&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can fly or you can go by bus. The bus from Santa Marta took us 19 hours and was 160.000 COP for both of us. Don&amp;#39;t forget that you can bargain at the counters. The initial price was 200.000 COP. Flight ticket would cost 250.000 COP p.p.. The bus was very comfortable with lot of space for legs, adjustable and comfy seats, Wi-fi and a toilet. However it was freezing cold in the bus due to the boosted air condition, very typical in Colombia. Wear a sweater, trousers, jacket and some blanket and you will be fine. The bus was operated by &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.expresobrasilia.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Brasilia company&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Metrocable and Parque Arvi&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take the metro to Acevedo station where you have to change to the cable car. The ticket for the metro is 2.000 COP and is valid also for the cable car until Santo Domingo station. For the cable car from Santo Domingo to Parque Arvi you have to pay 4.500 p.p. each way. It takes you up the hill, over a poor neighborhood. You will see almost the whole city from the cabin.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The park is huge, it has 16.000 hectares. You can enjoy more then 50 miles of hiking trails in a natural forest. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo de Antioquia and Plaza Botero&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This museum is located in the downtown. You can find expositions from Fernando Botero and Luis Caballero. Botero was born in Medellin and is one of the most important artists of Colombia. More then that, there is a hall with modern art of the XX. and XXI. century and a really nice exposition of pre-hispanic ceramics.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Most interesting to us was the temporary exhibition on the ground floor called Piso Piloto. The project was created in collaboration with Barcelona and it is dedicated to the housing issue of both cities. It&amp;#39;s shown in both cities simultaneously. Everyone has the right for a proper home and the truth is, that unfortunately the market is now controlled by brokers and &amp;quot;experts&amp;quot;, who don&amp;#39;t care about people and how they feel in their cities and their homes. The exposition showed interesting projects from students on how to resolve housing issues and make public space more open to people and their interactions. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Fernando Botero donated to Medellin and Bogota dozens of his sculptures and paintings. On Plaza Botero you can admire 23 big statues made by maestro Botero. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Real city walking tour&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We recommend to take the tour on your first days, as you will receive plenty of information and you will visit most of the interesting spots in downtown. The tour is a free tour, however you will be reminded by the guide several times that a tip is more then welcome and that 25.000 COP p.p. would be appropriate. You have to make a reservation on the internet in advance and the tour takes about 3 hours. Comparing this tour to other tours we have done before, this one was the least interesting mainly due to our guide, who treated us like children even calling us gringos and the facts she told us were oversimplified.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Guatape&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The bus leaves from Terminal Norte. Take the metro to Caribe station and go over the bridge to the terminal. It costs 11.500 COP p.p.. The bus drops you off close to the El Piedra (the rock). The bus ride takes around 2 hours. The entrance fee to El Piedra was 11.500 COP. Prepare yourself to walk 750 stairs to the very top. The view is fabulous and reminded us of Plitvicke lakes in Croatia. After El Piedra take a tuk-tuk to the center of Guatape for 10.000 COP. The center is very neat with colorful houses that are called Zocalos. On &amp;quot;plaza quatro esquinas&amp;quot; you can try the most amazing empanadas. An older lady fries them on a corner, with amazing fillings like tender beef and cheese. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;banner col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;banner col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape8.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape9.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape10.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape11.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape12.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape13.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape14.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Honestly, we spent so much money on parties, that we safe money on food and cooked in our hostel or we ate cheap street food. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Gourmet d&amp;#39;Andres&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They are opened till 16:00 and they serve breakfast and lunch. We haven&amp;#39;t had such high quality menu del dia in South America before. If you had enough of rice, beans and chicken, visit this nice restaurant and sit on the terrace. We ordered steak with potato pie, tuna steak with a fruit sauce and potato pie. The tuna steak was delicious and we loved the juicy piece of beef with red wine sauce. We got also a salad and a dessert. We paid 34.000 COP.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin16.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the backpacker hostels are located in El Poblado and the prices vary from 25.000 COP for a dorm to even 90.000 COP for a double room. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Kiwi hostel&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We didn&amp;#39;t book anything for the first night and we were really tired after a 19 hours bus ride from Santa Marta, that we decided to enjoy a little bit of luxury. We had a double room for 90.000 COP. We really appreciated the large bathroom with hot water and comfortable bed. The hostel has a small pool on the roof and two relaxation areas with hammocks. Breakfast is not included and costs about 6.000 COP, or you can cook your own meal in the kitchen. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Memphis hostel&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is one of the cheapest hostels in Poblado. A double room, costs 60.000 COP. We had our own bathroom and even a terrace. You can use the kitchen and they make coffee every morning for free.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The best party district is El Poblado, with many clubs, restaurants and bars.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Mansion club&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is an electronic music club in the center of El Poblado. Entrance fee was 15.000 COP. It opens on Fridays and Saturdays and the dj&amp;#39;s were playing on real turntables. We really enjoyed the set from the resident djane Juliana. The sound system could use an upgrade though. Insufficient base and lot of distortion. Check the lineup, they have international artists regularly.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/mansionclubmed&amp;quot;&amp;gt;mansion club&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/julianna&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dj julianna&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Parque Lleras&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This park is in the heart of El Poblado. People hangout in the park in the evening hours to share a bottle of rum, beers or micheladas. Michelada is beer mixed with lemon, chili and pepper and a pinch of salt on the cup. Our favorite Colombian beer is Club Colombia. They have three types, blond, red and black. Very popular is Aguardiente, which is very similar to French pastis. We prefer rum and one of the best ones is Ron Medellin. They sell one liter of Ron Medellin in a tetra pack for 34.000 COP.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin14.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Tayrona</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/tayrona.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/tayrona.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I went for a walk to the palm tree forest behind the beach, trying to find a fresh coconut. As I am walking under the trees I can hear coconuts falling down all the time. I must have picked up at least fifty coconuts to find out that all of them were either empty or rotten. Frustrated as I was, I went deeper to the forest to accomplish my silly mission. After a few minutes walk I came to an clearing with two huge piles of coconuts. On the left coconut shells, on the right heavy, ripe coconuts with liquid inside. I guess the locals have collected them and kept it there. With no one around to ask and to avoid any conflicts with he locals I replaced my empty coconut for the biggest and ripest one I could find from the pile. Perhaps the locals have counted them, who knows :)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;On the way back to the beach I was trying to throw the coconut against some rocks, smashing it with a pile of wood, hammering against it with a rock and bring Andrea the precious fruit inside. It did not work out. The shell consists of a thick layer of extremely rigid fibers, almost impossible to penetrate without any tools. Arriving at the beach with a bit of a frustration I took another approach. I started to work on the shell like a monkey with a branch and a sharp stone. Little by little I removed the fibers and was able to create an opening. With all my strength I started to remove big chunks of the shell to reveal the coconut inside. It must have taken me 40 minutes at least. Finally there it was in my hand, my own coconut. With a tiny branch I made a whole into the coconut to gain access to the liquid. To our surprise it contained at least 200 ml of fresh coconut water. A nice refreshment after all the hard work. Now it was only a piece of cake to crack the hard shell and to finally have a little snack. It was more then we could eat, so we offered a few pieces to our beach neighbors. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Tayrona national park is located on the northern Caribbean coast of Colombia. Tayrona has the most beautiful beaches that we have ever seen. The Guardian put the Tayrona beaches on the list of &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.theguardian.com/travel/2007/feb/16/beach.top10&amp;quot;&amp;gt;top ten beaches&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of the world.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Tayrona rain forest is home to capybaras (a large rodent), jaguars, monkeys, lizards and many sea species. If you walk quietly in the morning, you can get a glimpse of capybaras searching for food in the bushes, or of the monkeys jumping over the palm trees. The lizards and crabs can be spotted on many places along the paths.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;banner col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Transport&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take the bus from the market in Santa Marta for 6.000 COP. The ride takes around one hour. On the entrance to Tayrona national park you have to watch an informational video spot and the staff will give you a paper ticket to prove at the service desk, that you watched the video. With that you can go to the queue for the entrance tickets. They will also require an ID card or your passport. The entrance fee is 39.500 COP. We read on the internet, that you are not allowed to enter with plastic bags, which is not true. Neither did they require any vaccination documents. We saw two police officers checking sporadically tourists with large backpacks. Smuggling a small bottle of alcohol would not be too difficult.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After the entrance, take the small bus that will take you further into the National Park. It costs only 3.000 COP p.p and will save you at least 1 hour of boring walk on a paved road. The bus will drop you off close to the walking path. Prepare yourself for a trek of 3 hours in hot and humid conditions. You can rent a horse if you need to for 32.000 COP to the camp Cabo San Juan. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;What to pack&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We saw tourists with huge backpacks and also a suitcase. For a small fee you can leave your backpacks in your hotel in Santa Marta. We advice you to take a smaller backpack and to pack the following: &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;swimsuit&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;towel&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;headlamp&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;padlock for the locker&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;trousers and sweater for the night&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;t-shirts&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;repellent&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;camera&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;suncream is a must&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;toilet paper&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want to save money you also pack the following:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;5-liters of water per person&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;cans: tuna, sardines, beans etc...&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;bread, biscuits, sweets&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In the camp Cabo San Juan a 0.5l bottle of water costs 3.000 COP and the food is bad and expensive.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Camping&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can choose between two camps, Arrecifes and Cabo San Juan. We stayed in Cabo San Juan. Cabo San Juan is on the beach and it&amp;#39;s allowed to swim there, hwereas staying in Arrecifes you have to walk through the jungle for 15 min to get to Piscina beach, where you can swim safely. In Cabo San Juan you have 3 options:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Hammock 20.000 COP&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Tent 25.000 COP p.p.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cabana 50.000 COP p.p.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sleeping in the hammock is not for everyone. It can get cold in the nights and it&amp;#39;s not very comfortable. The tent has a dirty mattress though it protects you from mosquitoes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Facilities like shower, toilet and a small shop are available. For this prices we would expect a higher quality food and cleanliness. For example our last night only two toilets out of four were available. Four toilets are not sufficient for the capacity of the camp (more then 100 persons) and often we had to wait in a queue. In general the toilets were dirty except for 5 - 6 am in the morning right after the cleaning. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We heard from others, that Arrecifes is much cleaner.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona18.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In San Juan you can get food three times per day. Breakfast 6.000 COP for toast with marmalade or 10.000 COP for eggs, coffee and toast. Lunch and dinner are for 12.000 - 16.000 COP (fish, pork, chicken). Do not even bother to try the coffee or juices, they are watery and tasteless. On the way to Cabo San Juan stop by in Arrecifes for some refreshment, like fresh orange juice from Indians. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona16.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The whole place is an attractions. Incredible beaches and walking paths. The sea is so clean you can see the fish from above the surface. The water has so many colors turquoise, blue, light blue, white. Around the beach is the rain forest with lot of coconut palms, mangroves and rocks. The boulders are huge and flattened by the ocean and wind. They look surreal, like someone has placed them on the beach on purpose.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona17.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Snorkeling&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Along the coastline is a corral reef. Do not snorkel by yourself far away from the beach, the sea is rough with treacherous streams. The warning sings on the coast are a reminder of more then a hundred drowning victims. The ecosystem is so unique and protected, diving is prohibited. On the reception ask for the snorkeling expedition. It takes 2 hours and is absolutely worth the 40.000 COP p.p.. After a safety training with our guide we swam out towards the reef. We saw lot of colorful fish varieties, an octopus, corals, a huge sea snail and a sea snake. If you are lucky you might see manta rays and sea turtles.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;banner col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona9.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona10.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona11.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona12.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona13.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona14.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Santa Marta</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/santa_marta.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 3 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/santa_marta.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Lying on the Playa Blanca close to Rodadero, reading the first five pages of the Spanish-German text book, a local approached me. Andrea was swimming in the sea and with the little Spanish words that I know I had no clue what this person was talking. My first impression was that it is yet another annoying merchant offering souvenirs or a lunch in the beach restaurants. &amp;quot;Great, leave me alone, I don&amp;#39;t want to buy anything&amp;quot;, were my thoughts :) After several &amp;quot;no gracias&amp;quot; and him standing persistently above me I managed to figure out that he is actually asking me where I am from. He had recognized that I am reading a Spanish-German book and explained to me that he is Colombian born, living in Switzerland for the past 40 years. From that moment the conversation was easy as we switched to German. I felt a bit embarrassed that I rejected him in the first moments, but he understood that I don&amp;#39;t speak Spanish. He was so friendly, that he invited us to his beach tent where he offered us cold beers. Later on, we were invited to have lunch with his family in the nearby restaurant. We spent a lovely afternoon with his nice family laughing about our confusing introduction. A perfect example of Colombian hospitality. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There is not that much special about this city. First place in Colombia that we were not so happy to stay in. The historic center is very small, colonial and a bit similar to Cartagena but definitely not as pretty and neat as Cartagena. We spent four nights here to recover from a food poisoning after Minca. The harbor is located in the bay area next to the beach and close to the historic center. You can see large container ships sailing into the harbor and being un- and on-loaded. Santa Marta is a travel hub as you can depart from here to Tayrona, Minca and Guajirra. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;banner col-xs-12 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta13.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta14.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Playa Blanca&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take a bus to Rodadero (1.400 COP) and walk to the right end of the beach. There are several small ships that take you to Playa Blanca (10.000 COP return ticket). The beach is nice and clean and the water is warmer then in Taganga, nevertheless it can&amp;#39;t be compared with Playa Blanca in Cartagena. There are a dozen of restaurants that offer fresh fish. The boats return to Rodadero from 4pm.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Tayrona gold museum&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Compared to the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/blog/2015/bogota.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Museum of Gold&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in Bogota, this one is smaller and is showing similar gold artifacts. You can read on how the artifacts were made, about the techniques, decorations and rituals.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;One part of the Museum is dedicated to the history of Santa Marta and the liberation of slaves. The second floor is dedicated to Simon Bolivar. Probably the most interesting part of this museum is the exposition about indigenous people and their history in Sierra Nevada mountain region. We recommend to pay a visit to this exposition if you plan to go to Minca or Tayrona as you can get lot of information on the indigenous population that still lives in Sierra Nevada. Four indigenous groups live in Sierra Nevada: Kogui, Arhuaco, Wiwa, Arsario and Kankuamo. Social organization, clothing and language vary from group to group, but they share a common view of creation, the Law of Origin: this is a law that is written in every place on the Sierra and contains the principles and rules that govern the material and spiritual lives of the indigenous communities.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The indians chew coca leaves, which they mix with lime as they go about their daily activities on the Sierra. They keep the roasted coca leaves in shoulder bags, while the lime which they extract and put in their mouth with a wooden stick is kept in &amp;quot;poporos&amp;quot; - gourds. For indians, chewing coca leaves and using the gould lime container are fundamental aspects of their relationship with the spiritual world.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The poporo represents their &amp;quot;partner&amp;quot; and in &amp;quot;her&amp;quot; they keep their thoughts and their words, so they do not get carried away by the wind. Because of it vitamins and alkaloid components, coca helps them to remember and recite the myths and chants of &amp;quot;the ancients&amp;quot; during long nocturnal sessions.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Between the years 200 and 900 of our era, small groups settled around bays and in valleys on Sierra. They engaged in fishing, salt extraction, hunting, metal work... A number of transformations occurred from 900 A.D. onwards, which mark the beginning of the Tayrona Period. Greater complexity in stone construction, such as foundations of houses, pathways, public squares and agricultural terraces, together with the development of a notable hierarchical social structure and concentration of power, and new style of metal work. Food, raw materials, knowledge and manufactured objects were exchanged via social, political, economic and religious circuits which eventually came to link the Sierra with the entire Caribbean and the Eastern Cordillera. In 1501, the European conquistadors were amazed when they saw the Taiyronas, who fought them in violent war that lasted 75 years. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The admission is for free.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Cathedral&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Visit the cathedral and make some pictures. Simon Bolivar was buried here for several years. You can find a memorial plate inside the cathedral.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Cathedral&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Cathedral&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the restaurants are located on carrera 3 and around Parque de los Novios. Some of them are pretty good but pricey. Street food stands are mostly on carrera 5 and around the market. We saw stands with chorrizos and barbecue. The street food did not look very attractive so we skipped it this time.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Barbeque&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Barbeque&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Lulo cafe bar&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This restaurant is in the higher price range. The jugos are super tasty and served in jars. We loved it. We had the jugo combo, where you get the juice of the day, toasted bread, cream cheese with herbs and hummus for 8.000 COP. A fair deal.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The second time we came here, we chose the arepa with cheese, egg, bacon, beans and avocado (12.000 COP). Igor had a wrap with scrambled eggs, tomato, onion, ham, basil and cheese (14.000 COP). Portions are big and we had troubles to finish it. The food was delicious.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.lulocafebar.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lulo cafe bar&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta_lulo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Lulo cafe&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Lulo cafe&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Caribbean wings&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Decent and cheap food. They specialize in chicken wings and offer menu del dia as well. The food is fresh and you can see into the kitchen which is very clean. We went there twice. The prices for menu del dia are from 8.000 COP to 10.000 COP. We had the menu del dia with the chicken wings. They were freshly made, nice and crispy with platanos and rice on the side.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Calle 17 # 2- 59&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Miko&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This rooftop club is located on the left end of the beach in Santa Marta. Dj&amp;#39;s play from Thursday till Saturday. They offer only basic cocktails, but they are very strong and mixed with proper Rum/Vodka. The staff is friendly and the sound system is of high quality and powerful. They played different styles of electronic music. The night we have been there, they were playing house music. The next day when we were passing by, they were playing electro. The club is visited by upscale Colombians mixed with hipster tourists. Not our cup of tea but with the strong drinks and everyone around having fun and dancing we didn&amp;#39;t care about stereotypes and partied on.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.mikobar.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Miko&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Minca</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/minca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/minca.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We went for a walk to the river. On the way there we saw mangoes on the ground, unfortunately most of them were rotten or covered with insects. We did not give up and kept searching. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There is something about eating fresh handpicked fruit, full of taste and juice. It reminds you of the good old times spent in grandmothers garden. The taste of childhood that you can hardly find anywhere else. We felt like little children eating mangoes that we found on the ground directly under the tree. For the first time in our lives we tasted real fresh mangoes. It was a magic experience - sweet, juicy, soft and full of flavor, incomparable to mangoes that you can buy in Europe.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Wandering under the trees, looking for more mangoes a local approached us with a big smile and in his hands he was holding four big, ripe mangoes. Surprised as we were, we almost pulled out money to pay him. Minca people are friendly and forthcoming and they make you feel like home. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Mango&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Mango&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Transportation&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want to relax and run away from hot and busy Santa Marta, go to Minca. It is 40 minutes drive from Santa Marta. Since Minca is in the hills the temperatures are a bit cooler. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;To get there, go to the market in Santa Marta and ask for a car/jeep to Minca. They leave when the car is filled with passengers and they charge 7000 COP. Don&amp;#39;t forget to take enough cash with you, as there is no ATM in Minca.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Minca is a unique place to live. In the morning you can swim in the sea, for the lunch you can enjoy the rain forest and in the evening you can go for mountain biking in the hills. The mountain peaks of Sierra Nevada are covered with snow.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It&amp;#39;s one of the most beautiful places we&amp;#39;ve seen in Colombia. The flora in Minca has emerald green color and you can hear birds singing and the river flowing. It is a quiet and peaceful place. Sierra Nevada has a huge biodiversity and it is home to toucans, skunks, jaguars, monkeys, caimans and hummingbirds. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Indians consider Sierra Nevada to be the center of the world, or as they call it &amp;quot;pachamama&amp;quot;. It is understandable, the nature is very rich and provided the indigenous people with food for centuries.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Minca is also a well known coffee region with many coffee farms (fincas). Furthermore the cocoa plant grows wildly in Sierra Nevada.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is a small town 650 meters above the sea level. In the past it wasn&amp;#39;t the safest place, since F.A.R.C. (guerrilla group) was controlling this area. The locals told us that the police station was destroyed twice by bombs. The guerrillas were growing marijuana all over the area to finance the organization. The plants are still growing wildly in the forest and you can make out the distinct smell of it. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Nowadays everything is different. Minca is a safe place, visited by tourist every day. Several expats settled down here and build up hotels and restaurants in this little town.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Finca Victoria&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The finca is located 8 km from the village. You can either take a mototaxi (8.000 COP) or you can walk, like we did. It&amp;#39;s a bit difficult hike up the hills, especially in a hot day, but you will be rewarded with amazing views and if you are lucky you will see some animals on the way. We spotted a small armadillo in the bushes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The coffee farm was founded by an English family in 1892. Later on a German family, escaping from Europe because of world war II, took over the finca. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The finca is also home to a small brewery. The water comes from the river, the barley from Germany and hops from Czech Republic. They make two types. Happy tucan is a red ale and happy jaguar is a pilsner.The young German guy that owns the brewery knows how to make good beer. We give it a thumbs up.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The most important business of the finca is coffee production. They will explain you the whole process. From the harvest to cleaning coffee beans and sorting them by quality. At the end of the tour you will taste their coffee and you can buy some coffee. Astonishingly the whole farm is operated by 120 years old machines and a water turbine. They are not thinking about replacing them, the machines still do their job and the generated electricity powers the finca and the surrounding houses. The tour takes 40 minutes, it&amp;#39;s in Spanish and cost 10.000 COP p.p. Recently a group of French people opened a bistro in the finca, where you can buy beer from the local brewery and home made sandwiches.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cocoa workshop&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Arriving from Santa Marta to Minca, there are two houses on the right side. It&amp;#39;s a cafeteria serving home made cakes and coffee and selling chili sauces and chocolates. We bought a spicy mango-chili salsa. Next to the cafeteria is a small information stand. The guy there told us so many informations about history of Minca and about the local products (honey, salsas, coffee, chocolate products). It was a long but pleasant conversation and he didn&amp;#39;t force us to buy anything. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They are offering one day tours around Minca and Sierra Nevada. They will take you to Finca Victoria, Palo Alto (a view where you can see two highest mountains of Sierra Nevada-Colon and Bolivar), the waterfalls and a chocolate workshop. It costs 55.000 COP p.p. You can go by yourself and visit the places for free. The loop around minca is cca. 20km long. Ask for a map.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.junglejoeminca.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Jungle Joe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is offering bird watching excursions for 25.000 COP p.p.. There is a good chance he will be around since his office is also in the same house. Bird watching is every day from 6 a.m. and finish at 9 a.m. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The cocoa workshop was interesting. Firstly he gave us to try raw chocolate seeds and shells (they have high content of theobromine, a substance making people happy). Then he mixed grounded raw beans with coconut oil (it helps the product to stay solid, as coconut oil has solid form up to 25 degrees) and then we could choose the flavor. From three organic fruit marmalades we choose the blackberry one. Then he mixed everything, grounded the paste, put in a form and let it sit for 15 minutes in a freezer. It was delicious.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Pozo Azul&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This waterfall is located cca. one hour walk from Minca, on the way to Finca Victoria. You can swim in crystal clear water, but we have to say that it is very cold.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are a few hostels and hotels in all price categories. We heard that Casa Loma is a really cool place, they have amazing view, but the double rooms are very expensive. We chose Casa Colibri, which is just few minutes from Casa Loma. The owner is French and his wife Venezuelan. They are very friendly and we felt like at home. You can have a rest in a hammock and observe hummingbirds. Their breakfast is good. We had pancakes with fruits. The hostel is very clean and rooms have enough space. We paid around 60.000 COP per night for a double room. The breakfast is 5.000 COP.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are plenty of restaurants to choose from. On the way to Pozo Azul, just 15 minutes walking from Minca, is the restaurant Asador. We didn&amp;#39;t try but we passed by and it looked amazing. The chef was cutting big pieces of meat for the bbq. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Finca Victoria - French bistro&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They have homemade cakes, we tried their coffee cake. It was very good especially the topping with coffee flavor. We had the club sandwich with chicken, vegetables and egg and a croque-monsieur sandwich with dark bread, bechamel sauce and cheese and salad on the side. The bread is of European type and home made. With two happy tucan beers we paid 30.000 COP. A very pleasant change.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Finca Victoria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Finca Victoria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Happy Tucan Beer&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Happy Tucan Beer&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Taganga</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/taganga.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/taganga.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Taganga is a small hippie/fisherman village close to Santa Marta. To get there, catch a collectivo bus anywhere in Santa Marta, it cost 1.400 COP p.p. (0.50 EUR) or take a taxi. It&amp;#39;s just a few minutes drive from the city.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Taganga is a party place. You will meet interesting travelers and hippies and you will probably extend your stay like we did. You plan to come for few days and you might stay for few weeks, like many of the guests we met at the hostels, or as one of the locals explained to us: &amp;quot;You come to Taganga normal, you leave crazy, you come to Taganga crazy, you leave normal&amp;quot;. With the good vibes of this small fishing village you will loose track of time. You can ask around for a volunteering job in the hostels and get a dorm bed and one meal per day in exchange for 6 hours work five days per week. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Transportation&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you go from Cartagena and you want to travel cheap, take the collectivo (small bus that stops anywhere) for 1.800 COP to bus terminal, the ride from the center takes around 1 hour. Once you have arrived at the bus terminal, ignore hustlers and any friendly advisors and go straight to the counters. Ask for a direct bus to Santa Marta. We went with Berlinave for 20.000 COP p.p. (7 EUR) in a bus with AC and a toilet. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Beaches&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The local beach one is not the most picturesque, however there are plenty of restaurants and bars and the water is clean. You can always go to Playa Grande, which is much cleaner. Don&amp;#39;t listen to any advisors and walk there. It will take you just 15 minutes and it&amp;#39;s doable in flip flops. Advantage of going by foot, is the beautiful view over the village and the bay. The path to Playa Grande starts at the very far right of the local beach, just below the hotel that is located on the hill side. At the playa are several restaurants and seats to rent. Swimming at Playa Grande reminded us of swimming in a lake, because the water is so calm and cool. It can be crowded and loud on the weekends, so it&amp;#39; s better to continue your way further around the bay and find &amp;quot;your beach&amp;quot;. Further out are a few small, hidden beaches with only a handful of people. It would be a perfect place, if the hills were not covered with plastic bottles and trash. We think that the people are missing environmental education and we hope that this will change one day. The village is still unspoiled by mass tourism. There are no big hotels or posh restaurants. On the contrary, we hope this won&amp;#39;t change!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you stay during the weekend book a room in advance. There are plenty of cheap hostels, some of them are dirty and half empty and you can&amp;#39;t really socialize. If you are a party animal and you don&amp;#39;t mind to be nonstop with people, go to the hostel Nirvana. They have only dormitories with 15 bunk beds, a swimming pool in the courtyard. Most of the guests are in their twenties.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;If you want a nice, cozy and quiet place, go to the Garden House hostel or the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.lacasadefelipe.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;San Felipe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; hostel. We stayed at San Felipe. It&amp;#39;s a bit more expensive for Taganga, 65.000 COP (22.60 EUR) per night for a double room, but it is worth it. You have your own bathroom with a toilet, fan and a safe. It&amp;#39;s located at the foot of a hill. It has a &amp;quot;mirador&amp;quot;, a terrace with a view over the see, where you can relax in hammocks. You can use a kitchen and a lounge with TV as well. The breakfast cost from 4.000 COP to 7.000 COP. We loved their coffee. This was by far the cleanest Hotel on our trip in Colombia.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We also stayed three nights in Alquimista hostal, which is one of the cheapest in the village. They have dorms in the main building, where you can also find a patio with kitchen, bar, TV and couches. The price of a dorm bed with AC is 18.000 COP (6.30 EUR) per night, but we recommend you to find a buddy and rent a double room. The double rooms (3 in total) are located in another building, just 50 meters from the main one, so it&amp;#39;s more quiet. It costs 39.000 COP (13.50 EUR) per night, so there is almost no difference in the price. There is a lounge, terrace, kitchen and a bathroom. Breakfast is included.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The drinks on the bar are very cheap. Carlos, the manager, employs young volunteers who speak English. We had a lot of fun here and we were coming back even when we were staying in San Felipe.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Street food is available at the entire beach promenade. You can get arepas, tortillas or sausages and fresh juices and cocktails. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Dunkarinka&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The best fish we&amp;#39;ve had in Colombia. Go for menu del dia and ask what fish they have on menu. We were in Colombia in the season of mojarra, which is a good average fish. For a change we put a little bit more money and we ordered the sierra fish. It&amp;#39;s a big fish with enough meat for two people. Like always it came with coconut rice, salad and a fish soup and we paid 15.000 COP (5,20 EUR) p.p. They will also ask you how you want it to be prepared. We tried fried and barbecued fish before, so this time we ordered it cooked in a vegetable salsa. The salsa was delicious, the fish juicy, soft like butter and not greasy like when fried.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/fish_sierra1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/fish_sierra2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Don&amp;#39;t go to &amp;quot;Barracuda&amp;quot;, terrible service and the worst food what we&amp;#39;ve had here. &amp;quot;Yammy Yammy&amp;quot; wasn&amp;#39;t bad and it&amp;#39;s cheap, we enjoyed their juices.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The gringo discos by the beach playing &amp;quot;international music&amp;quot; (Rihanna, David Guetta, Pit bull and other commercial crap). If you ask around, you can find nice parties, especially on the weekends. We were in the Compass bar, it&amp;#39;s located up the hill nearby the football playground. It&amp;#39;s a garden bar and sometimes they have live music. We were there for a concert of cumbia music, the band is called Kumbia Kuatika. The band is originally from Argentina. They play traditional Peruvian cumbia. Their repertoire includes big classics of Peruvian and Colombian cumbia or &amp;quot;chicha&amp;quot; but mostly they play their own songs. The music is very live and temper and that&amp;#39;s what we like.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Kumbia Kuatika - &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/kumbia.kuatika&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Facebook&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; | &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IEgbCgCr864&amp;quot;&amp;gt;YouTube&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will be offered a variety of substances in Taganga. It&amp;#39;s your choice, but what we heard is not reasonable to walk around with it in the night. The everywhere present police can stop and frisk you and then escort you to the ATM...&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/cartagena.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 8 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/cartagena.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/cartagena_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Playa Blanca&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are several ways how to get to Playa Blanca. You can either buy a tour from guides on the street, in your hostel or you can get there on your own with a bus and a boat. We read on the internet that you can try to find a spot on a boat close to Mercado Bazurto and you don&amp;#39;t have to pay 12.000 COP (4.20 EUR) park fee. Afterwards we met other travelers, who confirmed that it is possible to get to Playa Blanca on your own for 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR) one way p.p. and sleep in a hammock for 20.000 COP (7 EUR) per night.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We chose the easy way and booked a tour for 85.000 COP (29.50 EUR) p.p. including transportation and accommodation for one night on Playa Blanca. The chartered bus took us to a small harbor, where a boat was waiting for us. The ride with the boat takes around 1 hour. We stayed at &amp;quot;Hostal Playa Blanca&amp;quot; in a small hut-like room (cabana). All hostels are located directly on the beach 10m max from the sea. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The beach is amazing, the sand is almost white and the water warm and turquoise. The locals stay on one side of the beach which is very crowded. Most of the hostels are on the other side of the beach where it is more quiet and not that busy. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will find various restaurants and stands with food on Playa Blanca. We recommend to go to the part where the locals are staying and where you can order a plate with fresh fish for 10.000 - 12.000 COP (3.50 - 4.20 EUR). In the evening the prices can double. The salesmen with the stalls offer overpriced shrimps or langustas (from august), but you can always bargain with them. We wanted a portion of shrimps and the merchant started with 30.000 COP. We were able to negotiate it down to 15.000 COP (5.20 EUR). Same goes for cocktails. They can prepare fancy cocktails for you served in a pineapple or coconut. We bargained the price for two pineapple pia coladas to 23.000 COP (8 EUR), 7.000 COP less then the initial price. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can rent a jet ski for 30.000 COP (10.50 EUR) per 15 minutes. We borrowed snorkels, but we did not see anything interesting on the sea bed.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/playa_blanca1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/playa_blanca2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;City center&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The historic center is small and is surrounded by city walls. The architecture is similar to southern cities in Spain. The buildings have nice, refreshing patios and the balconies are covered with flowers. Just take a camera and get lost for few hours. This district is posh and bit more expensive then the rest of the city. You can find very expensive restaurants, boutique hotels and jewelery shops, specialized in emeralds. We saw nice design shops selling original swimsuits, shoes and hand made jewelery. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want to save money you can eat on the street or find restaurants that offer menu del dia and live in a hostel at district Getsemani. Unfortunately we didn&amp;#39;t have enough time to explore Getsemani. It&amp;#39;s covered with street art, we saw pieces from Bogotas artist DjLu on Calle de la Sierpe. Visit Plaza de la Trinidad in the evening hours, where locals hang out. Have some fresh arepas or hamburgers from the stalls. Afterwards you can go to one of the many bars, they have happy hours for cocktails and special offers, like 2 for 20.000 COP (7 EUR). We heard that on Calle Arsenal has several cool clubs.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/cartagena_center1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/cartagena_center2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Naval museum&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It&amp;#39;s located in the historic center and the admission is 8.000 COP (2.80 EUR) p.p.. The museum has two large wings. The lower one is dedicated to the naval history of Colombia and especially Cartagena de Indias. You could spend hours reading the information boards, few of them are in English. The second wing is dedicated to the modern Colombian navy. We had lot of fun in a model of submarine command bridge, pushing buttons, playing with periscope and shooting enemy ships. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.museonavaldelcaribe.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.museonavaldelcaribe.com/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Try some fresh fish or sea food you are on the coast after all. When we were there in July it was the season for Mujarra, a very tasty fish. Menu del dia will set you back 10.000-15.000 COP. In the evening the street sellers offer classic arepa con queso (grilled corn paddy filled with cheese) for 1.000 COP (0.35 EUR). Besides that they offer meat sticks, potatoes filled with meat or fried cheese rolls. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/food1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mujarra Fish&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mujarra Fish&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Restaurante Atahualpa&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We chose the menu with fish for 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR). The fish soup was very good with whole pieces of meat and yuka, sprinkled with cilantro leaves and lime juice. The main course consists of fish, rice, beans in a sauce and pickled vegetables. The portions were big. We also recommend to try their lulu juice. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/food2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Food&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Food&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Bogota</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/bogota.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/bogota.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/bogota_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo Botero&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.banrepcultural.org/museo-botero&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.banrepcultural.org/museo-botero&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the items in this museum were donated by the famous Colombian artist Fernando Botero. This museum is for free and it also houses a numismatic museum. Botero has a very distinct style and you might find that he is obsessed with painting fat people. Botero said about his figures, What I say is that they are not fat, but voluminous. If I make a fruit, a landscape, an animal, a man, anything, it is a deformation to exalt volume. So I do not see them as fat, but as voluminous. Fat can also be Michelangelo, Masaccio or all Florentine art that is voluminous.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Besides Boteros paintings and sculptures you can admire paintings from Picasso, Gustav Klimt, Max Ernst, Joan Miro, Salvador Dal and many more. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/botero_horse.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Boteros Horse&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Botero Horse&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/botero_monalisa.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Botero Monalisa&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Boteros Monalisa&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/joan_miro.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Joan Miro&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Joan Miro&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo del oro (Museum of gold)&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is the biggest museum of gold in South America. It displays thousands of gold, silver and coper artifacts from the ancient indian history. Not only can you admire the artifacts but the exhibition tells a story on how the objects were made and how they were used in ceremonies and what spiritual role they played in the life of the ancient people.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can read about priests and shamans who identified them selfs with bats, evoked this animal habits in they own, they lived in dark temples, worked at night and flew when they were in transes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Yopo, a powerful hallucinogen that was extracted from the Anadenanthera tree, came from the Eastern Plains. It was inhaled using a small spoon or bird bone from trays with animals depicted on them that conjured up images of the transformations that were experienced.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The entry fee is only 3.000 COP (1 EUR)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/museo_del_oro.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Museo del oro&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Museo del oro - trays and bones for snorting&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Monserrate&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Monserrate is the hill above Candelaria and the city center. You can either access it by walking up the very steep steps (at least 60 min. hard climbing) or you can go for the easier option and take the cable car. The costs for the cable car is 8.500 COP (3 EUR) one way. You can return walking (30 min.). The return ticket is 17.000 COP (6 EUR). On the top of the hill are a monastery, small botanic garden and a market with hand crafted products and food. The view of the city is spectacular.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;National Museum&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is admission free and currently undergoing a reconstruction. Most of the descriptions and informations are written only in Spanish. However there is one remarkable exhibition room with marvelous paintings and projections which does not require any explanations. We have never before seen an exhibition room like this. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/national_museum.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;National Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;National Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Graffiti tour&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Meeting point is at Plaza de Periodistas at 10am or 2pm nearby the statue of Simon Bolivar. The tour takes around 2.5 hours and goes through La Candeleria district and finishes in downtown. Be prepared to hear tons of informations not only on the graffiti and the artists but also on social and economic issues of Bogota. Other then that you will get tips on restaurants, bars, alternative shops and galleries. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Street art in Bogota is nowadays well established and recognized by its citizens, landlords and shop owners. Street art is present everywhere but especially in Candelaria, where artists can even work by daylight in safe zones. Some landlords choose to commission international artists to avoid having their facade being tagged. Once the facade is covered with a piece, other artists respect it and they don&amp;#39;t paint over it. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will see pieces from Guecho, Rodez, Crisp, Likme, APC, Bastardia, DjLu,&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Even though the tour is free a tip of 20.000 - 30.000 COP (7 - 10 EUR) is appropriate.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art - La Candelaria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art - La Candelaria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art - Toxicomano&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art - Toxicomano&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Candelaria&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the historic center of Bogota. Some of the colonial houses are dating back 500 years. There are no two identical buildings. You will find many design shops, cheap hostels, restaurants and bars over there. Most of the historic monuments (Plaza Bolivar, Museo Botero, Monserrate ... ) are in walking distance.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Several universities are located in the Candelaria district. Many students and young people come to Plaza de Quevedo to enjoy street performances (mostly live music) and drinks (chicha, aquardiente or beer). This is definitely one of the best hot spots to meet with locals and have a drink.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We stayed in Casa Quevedo that is located at the Plaza de Quevedo and the party is right outside the door. Prices are around 50.000 COP (17 EUR) for a double room per night, breakfast included (eggs, bread, coffee). The 2nd floor has only two toilets which were not always clean.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Typical dishes from Bogota are Bandeja Paisa, which consists of meat, sausage, rice and beans and Aijaco, which is a soup with corn, yucca, potatoes and meat. If you are into sweats Columbia has a lot to offer. You can try pastry and cakes from tamarind, dulce de leche (caramelized condensed milk) and different types of fruit.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;When in Bogota try Chicha drink. It is fermented corn alcohol beverage, very sweet and sour. From Plaza Quevedo leads a narrow street in which every pub and bar serves this drink in a cup made out of totumo. Totumo is a typical plant for Colombia. Be warned that the portion is really big and not everyone likes the taste.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/food1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Aijaco Soup&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Aijaco Soup&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Dos Gatos y Simone&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is a cozy restaurant and the food is good. It is easy to miss, because it is all painted with graffiti from the outside. We chose estofado, which is meat with rice, some veggies, guacamole and salsa. The meat was tender and juicy, the sauce and the guacamole were nicely seasoned and tasty. One meal was with 20.000 COP (7 EUR) a bit pricey for Bogota.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Tao Calentao&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The biggest problem with this place is to find it. It&amp;#39;s hidden in small alley close to Universidad de Los Andes. Ask the students around they will point you in in the right direction. Calentao is a typical Colombian dish from rice, meat, beans and vegetables. You can select all ingredients yourself, or choose from one of the four versions on the menu (Argentinian, Thai, Mexican, Italian ). This is a bistro style and the food is prepared in front of you. Prices are reasonable and the portions are huge. We had troubles to finish our meals. We paid 28.000 COP (9.70 EUR) for two meals with lemonade.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Plaza de Mercado de Paloquemao&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The market is far from the center. Getting there on foot is possible, but don&amp;#39;t draw too much attention onto yourself as you are walking through some shady neighborhoods. It&amp;#39;s located on the corner of Carrera 28 and Calle 19 in front of a modern shopping center. The market offers a large selection of fruits, vegetables and herbs. Inside the market you will find several stands with authentic, home made cuisine. We had two soups, two main dishes (large portion of fried and barbecued chicken leg, lentils, platano and arepa) and lemonade. Altogether we paid only 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR). The portions were big and the locals were super friendly to us. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/berlin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/berlin.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;When one of our best friends moved to Berlin, we knew that sooner or later we will come to visit him. Andrea has never been to Berlin before. She loves techno music, art and good food, so for her Berlin was a must-do-trip. Berlin is incredibly cheap, provided you eat on the street, drink beer (not cocktails) and you stay in a hostel rather then a hotel. In that case you can experience Berlin on a budget. Berlin offers lot of fun activities and attractions. To visit all of the techno clubs in Berlin, would be our favorite choice. However, if you are not into electronic music, Berlin offers lot of exhibitions, galleries, museums, concerts and a free street art tour, which we highly recommend. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can find more information here:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.visitberlin.de/en/see/museums-art/art&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.visitberlin.de/en/see/museums-art/art&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.exberliner.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.exberliner.com/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Free street art tour&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you like street art, join the alternative Berlin tour. Our guide Carl from Scotland who really loves this city and obviously knows a lot about the history and its underground subcultures. The tour started in the center, district Mitte. He showed us pieces from El Bocho, Sobre, Mr. Six and others. Then we moved on to the most &amp;quot;alternative&amp;quot; district, Kreuzberg. Since the tour we have looked at the city with different eyes, looking for art everywhere. We really appreciated that we were a small group about ten people and we didn&amp;#39;t disturb people around, because every time we kept distance. We also got tips about good restaurants and clubs where to go. This was a free tour and the three hours passed quickly, however we were very satisfied and left a tip and so did the rest of our group. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;East Side Gallery&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the longest open air gallery in the world with the most bitter history. That wall used to divide the city in two parts, the western and the eastern communist world. Many people died trying to cross it. Some of those who managed to flee had to leave rest of their families behind. It is the longest piece of the original Berlin wall with 101 murals from artists from all over the world and of course it is for free. It&amp;#39;s located in Mhlenstrae in Berlin Friedrichshain. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.eastsidegallery-berlin.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;East Side Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Techno clubs&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We have visited three clubs in two days, but you can go nonstop from Friday till Monday and there are so many of them that you won&amp;#39;t know what to choose. Of course you can use &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Residentadvisor&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; but even better is to ask the locals for the most recent hot spots, because some of them are very touristy and that&amp;#39;s not the best you can get. You can try to get to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.berghain.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Berghain&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, but count on a 2 hours queue and strong possibility that the bouncers wont let you in. Don&amp;#39;t go in large groups, and try to be of mixed gender, dressed preferably in dark clothes. Don&amp;#39;t draw too much attention on you, by speaking loudly or by being obviously drunk. Very popular and good techno clubs in the city are &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://aboutparty.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;://about blank&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.sisyphos-berlin.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sysiphos&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.kitkatclub.org/Home/Club/Index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Kitkat&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.water-gate.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Watergate&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We started on Saturday midnight in &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://tresorberlin.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tresor&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and we were a bit too early, because the club was almost empty. On the other hand it was easy and quick to get in because there was no queue. Tresor is totally worth to see! Its dark, very charismatic and industrial. The void audio sound systems on both stages rocks.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Later that night we moved on to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://griessmuehle.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Griessmuehle&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, which was probably one of our best techno events ever. We stayed only for three hours but it was a total blast. The club was hosting dj&amp;#39;s and producers from the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/lobster-theremin&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lobster Theremin&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; label. We are not sure if it was just because we were lucky to listen to such high quality techno music or if the club is organizing high class events like this every week. It was simply amazing. The interior and exterior is supporting this raw dirty techno atmosphere. There were no lights, no strobos on the main stage, just a bit of light from the bar which intensified the atmosphere. Be careful on the toilets which are the worst we have ever seen:) You can also chill out in the sun outside by the river.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Sunday night all major clubs play mostly minimal techno or housy music. Since we are not the biggest fans of that, we decided to go to the club R19, which turned out to be a mistake. Please don&amp;#39;t go there! Just if you like bad music, cyber techno or psytrance (I think it&amp;#39;s the same) and you can deal with weird people. Anyway it was an experience.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tresor&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/mixmag-1/imprint-100-lobster-theremin-label-mix-by-asquith&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lobster Theremin set&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.monsieurvuong.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Monsieur Vuong&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Alte Schoenhauser Str. 46&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Super fast service and good quality food. The food came five minutes after we have ordered. You can choose from a daily menu or order a la carte and the prices are more then reasonable, from 5-10 EUR. We ordered chicken with mango and minced meat rolls with noodles and fresh vegetables. Both dishes and the home made lemonade were super fresh. The Pho soup was ok, we have had better though. The service was efficient and nice. For two daily menu dishes, the pho soup and two home made lemonades we paid 33 EUR.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.curry36.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Curry 36&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Mehringdamm 36 und Bahnhof Zoologischer Garten&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;They claim that it is the best curry wurst in the city, The sauce was obviously home made and Andrea chose an organic sausage which was juicy and soft. For a middle sized sausage with fries we paid 3,50 EUR. Nice and cheap lunch. 10 meters from Curry 36 is probably one of the best places to eat kebab but prepare yourself to wait for at least 30 minutes, it is called Mustafa. We were standing by watching people getting their kebabs and they looked awesome, very fresh and in big sizes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.burgermeister.berlin/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Burgermeister&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Oberbaumstrasse 8&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;This is very nice and cheap fast food in the Kreuzberg district. I would appreciate a bigger portion of meat, but what can you ask for if you pay 4 EUR for a burger. The bun was delicious and obviously home made, the fries were also very good. Waiting in the queue, ordering and preparation time, all together it took max 20 minutes to get our food.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Burger from Burgermeister&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Burger from Burgermeister&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;What movies to watch and what to listen before (or while) you go&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Baader_Meinhof_Complex&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Baader Meinhof Complex (2008)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. is a 2008 German film by Uli Edel. Written and produced by Bernd Eichinger, it stars Moritz Bleibtreu, Martina Gedeck, and Johanna Wokalek. The film is based on the 1985 German best selling non-fiction book of the same name by Stefan Aust. It retells the story of the early years of the West German far-left militant group the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rote_Armee_Fraktion&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Rote Armee Fraktion&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (Red Army Faction, or RAF) from 1967 to 1977. The film was nominated for Best Foreign Language Film at the 81st Academy Awards. It was also nominated for the Golden Globe in the Best Foreign Language Film category.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Lives of Others&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (German: Das Leben der Anderen) is a 2006 German drama film, marking the feature film debut of filmmaker Florian Henckel von Donnersmarck, about the monitoring of East Berlin by agents of the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stasi&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stasi&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Germany&amp;quot;&amp;gt;GDR&amp;#39;s&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; secret police. It stars Ulrich Mhe (who died within a year of the film&amp;#39;s release) as Stasi Captain Gerd Wiesler, Ulrich Tukur as his superior Anton Grubitz, Sebastian Koch as the playwright Georg Dreyman, and Martina Gedeck as Dreyman&amp;#39;s lover, a prominent actress named Christa-Maria Sieland. The film was released in Germany on 23 March 2006. At the same time, the screenplay was published by Suhrkamp Verlag. The Lives of Others won the 2006 Academy Award for Best Foreign Language Film. The film had earlier won seven Deutscher Filmpreis awardsincluding those for best film, best director, best screenplay, best actor, and best supporting actorafter setting a new record with 11 nominations. It was nominated for Best Foreign Language Film at the 64th Golden Globe Awards.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Run_Lola_Run&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Run Lola Run&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (German: Lola rennt, literally &amp;quot;Lola runs&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Lola is running&amp;quot;) is a 1998 German thriller film written and directed by Tom Tykwer and starring Franka Potente as Lola and Moritz Bleibtreu as Manni. The story follows a woman who needs to obtain 100,000 Deutsche Mark in twenty minutes to save her boyfriend&amp;#39;s life. The film&amp;#39;s three scenarios are reminiscent of the 1981 Krzysztof Kielowski film Blind Chance; following Kielowski&amp;#39;s death.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Good Bye, Lenin![1] is a 2003 German tragicomedy film. Directed by Wolfgang Becker, the cast includes Daniel Brhl, Katrin Sa, Chulpan Khamatova, and Maria Simon. Most scenes were shot at the Karl-Marx-Allee in Berlin and around Plattenbauten near Alexanderplatz.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christiane_F.__We_Children_from_Bahnhof_Zoo&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Christiane F.  Wir Kinder vom Bahnhof Zoo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is a 1981 German film directed by Ulrich Edel that portrays the drug scene in West Berlin in the 1970s, based on the non-fiction book of the same name written following tape recordings of teenage girl Christiane F. The movie immediately acquired cult status (which it still retains today) and features David Bowie as both himself and the soundtrack composer, which gave the movie a commercial boost. Both the movie and the book acquired cult status in Europe immediately after release, raising awareness of heroin addiction. The popularity of the movie was greatly boosted by David Bowie&amp;#39;s participation as both himself (portrayed giving a concert early in the movie) and as the main contributor to the soundtrack. Bowie&amp;#39;s music from his albums made in Berlin during 1976-77 is heavily featured throughout the picture, and as he was at the very peak of his popularity during the late 1970s-early 1980s, his presence helped boost the film&amp;#39;s commercial success.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/baader_meinhof_complex.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Baeder Meinhof Komplex&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/good_bye_lenin.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Baeder Meinhof Komplex&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ben Klock&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/benklock&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/benklock&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/ben-klock&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/ben-klock&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Rdhd&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/rodhad&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/rodhad&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/rodhad&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/rodhad&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Marcel Dettman&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/marceldettmann&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/marceldettmann&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/marceldettmann&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/marceldettmann&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sven Vath&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/svenvath&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/svenvath&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/hightension1053/sven-vath-live-time-warp-2015-mannheim-germany-06-04-2015&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/hightension1053/sven-vath-live-time-warp-2015-mannheim-germany-06-04-2015&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Motor city drum ensemble&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/mcde&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/mcde&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/platform/motor-city-drum-ensemble-dekmantel&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/platform/motor-city-drum-ensemble-dekmantel&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Chris Liebing&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrisliebing&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrisliebing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/chris-liebing&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/chris-liebing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Pan Pot&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/pan-pot&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/pan-pot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/pan-pot&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/pan-pot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ostgut ton&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/record-label.aspx?id=803&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/record-label.aspx?id=803&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/ostgutton-official&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/ostgutton-official&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Cassy&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/cassy&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/cassy&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/cassy-official-1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/cassy-official-1&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

  </channel> 
</rss>
