<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JBake</title>
    <link>http://www.viabohemia.net</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.viabohemia.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <description>JBake Bootstrap Template</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 11:48:15 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 11:48:15 -0300</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Paracas &amp; Huacachina		</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/paracas.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/paracas.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We arrived to Huacachina, an oasis in the desert. Huacachina is close to Ica. As we already had a bus ticket Ica - Cusco, we wanted to visit Huacachina. We had just one day and night for the popular activities there: buggy ride and sand boarding. We arrived to Huacachina just half an hour before the start of the tour. We read some reviews on Internet and we assumed that the trip booked directly in our hostel &amp;quot;The desert nights&amp;quot; should be fine.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;We jumped in to the buggy and we drove off to the dunes. We arrived at the dunes and the driver tried to drive uphill, but the engine could not deliver its full power and we started to go backwards. He tried it once more with a longer approach. No success, there was obviously something wrong. We stopped and he cleaned the air filter. We were sad, we knew that we can not prolong our stay. All the other buggies left and we were stuck in a dune. The driver realized he can&amp;#39;t solve the issue in the dunes. He turned around back to the oasis to switch the car. &amp;quot;Yuppi!&amp;quot; This time the car sounded more solid and powerful and once again we started to enjoy the ride. All of a sudden, right in the ascend on a dune, he killed the engine. He tried to start it several times, we could hear that this one will not go anywhere.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;To our surprise he stopped another passing by buggy and the driver agreed to take us on board. We were joking with the other passengers that for sure this buggy will brake in a few minutes again. Luckily that didn&amp;#39;t happen and it turned out to be an awesome ride. The driver was going crazy, we were jumping up and down in the buggy, flying over the dunes, laughing and screaming. This buggy was super fast and furious, like out of a mad max movie.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;First we visited Paracas. This coastal city is interesting because of two things, the natural reserve Paracas and the Islas Ballestas. Be aware that the restaurants are more expensive then in Lima (talking about the middle range).&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The Huacachina oasis is located very close to the city of Ica and is famous for sand boarding and buggy rides. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Paracas from Lima&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are many companies going to Paracas from Lima. There is no direct connection, instead you buy a ticket to Pisco, which is 20km from Paracas. We chose Flores for 18 PEN p.p. The ride took about four hours. From Pisco you have to take a collectivo or a buseta to Paracas. We arrived in the night and there were no busetas, we were forced to take a taxi for 25 PEN.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Sea lions&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Sea lions&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Huacachina from Paracas&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;First you need to get to Pisco. We took a collectivo (basically every car heading that direction, honking on people) for 4.50 p.p. We told him that we need to go to Ica and he dropped us off at the taxi terminal. A taxi took us for 9 PEN to the bus terminal. From the terminal the buses leave every fifteen minutes to Ica. We went with Peru bus for 5 PEN p.p. In Ica we took a moto taxi to Huacachina for 5 PEN. This whole journey took about four hours. The tourist office in Huacachina offered us the same trip in a private transport for 20 USD. Well, we were happy to save the money for other activities.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions in Paracas&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Islas Ballestas&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are many agents and companies offering the tour, the prices can vary depending on agent, season and departure time. The tourists go together on one boat that leaves from the peer. We bargained the price to 65 PEN for both of us for the afternoon tour. The morning tour is supposed to be cheaper. The value for the money was awesome anyway. The boat was new and it felt safe. First we saw the Paracas Candelabra, a geoglyph and a good alternative to the Nazca lines, if you don&amp;#39;t have time/money. This ancient geoglyph is 60 m long. The age is unknown but it could be more then two thousand years old. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Candelabra&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Candelabra&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Then we headed to the Ballestas islands. We saw dozens of sea lions, penguins and many different bird species. We got very close to the sea lions. They are used to tourists. Unimpressed they continued their afternoon siesta, not paying much attention to us. Two of them showed us their gigantic teeth in a face to face argument. They were absolutely awesome and adorable. They do smell...terribly!:)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The whole trip took about two hours.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Islas Ballestas&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Islas Ballestas&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Islas Ballestas&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Islas Ballestas&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Islas Ballestas&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Islas Ballestas&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Paracas natural reserve&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There is a lot to explore in this protected area. Unfortunately, we had just one short afternoon to. We rented bicycles in the city and explored the park on our own. We recommend to invest a bit more money in the rental bikes. We rented two crappy bikes for 25 PEN.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The entrance fee to the park is 15 PEN p.p. This was a combined ticket, valid also for Islas Ballestas. It saved us 5 PEN p.p. Our first stop was at the museum where we spend two hours. The museum is dedicated to Paracas marine and &amp;quot;desert&amp;quot; life. It was very organized and informative. We continued to the Playa Roja. This beach got the name for its red colored sand. The waves and wind were very strong. The name Paracas came from the indigenous languages and you could translate it into &amp;quot;raining sand&amp;quot; - how appropriate.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Paracas Natural Reserve&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Paracas Natural Reserve&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Paracas Natural Reserve&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Paracas Natural Reserve&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions in Huacachina&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Buggy riding and sand boarding&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are several agencies providing this tour. We described our experience with &amp;quot;Desert nights&amp;quot; in our story above. You will make a few stops on the dunes for the sand boarding. Igor is an experienced snowboarder, he took a snowboard from the Hostel. The rest of us enjoyed sliding on the boards belly down. Igor admitted that the snowboard was very slow on the sand. The sand boards were much faster and because the dunes are very big, we could achieve high speeds. In the end you can admire a spectacular sun set in the desert. The whole tour took around 3 hours. We received a free Pisco Sour in our Hostel. The trip costs 50 PEN p.p.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Buggy&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food in Paracas and Huacachina&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;La Pequena Brisa, stand 2&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This was our best food in Paracas. We had menu del dia - Ceviche and Chicharron de Mariscos, Inca Cola. Everything was very fresh and especially the Ceviche was delicious. The restaurant looked very clean. We tried other restaurants in Paracas but we were not satisfied with them. We had a hamburger in Huacachina in our hostel &amp;quot;Desert nights&amp;quot; and it was absolutely disgusting. As much as we loved the stuff and atmosphere there, the food and cocktails could be better.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/paracas/paracas13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Ceviche&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Ceviche&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay in Paracas&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Backpackers house the Pacific&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Paracas is very small city, you can walk everywhere. This hostel was located close to the center and the owners were very kind. The first night we spent in a double room with private bathroom. Second night in a twin room with shared bathroom. We would recommend the double room for 60 PEN. The twin room cost 40 PEN, but the walls don&amp;#39;t have any isolation and you hear every word from the reception. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay in Huacachina&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Desert nights&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This hostel has only dormitories with 8 bunk beds. Huacachina is expensive and we couldn&amp;#39;t afford to stay in a double room. In the end, we were happy because we met very nice people. The stuff is super friendly, English speaking and funny. Anyway, you will probably stay only one night in the oasis so this type of accommodation is good enough. We paid 20 PEN p.p. They have happy hours and serve cocktails on the bar.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Lima					</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/lima.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/lima.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We stayed in Lima with a really great guy, who showed us around the city. We were drinking and partying together. We met through couchsurfing and he helped us to experience Lima like a local. One evening he did not feel well and couldn&amp;#39;t join us for drinks, so he called his friend Niky to go out with us. We understood each other well and the time was flying. We visited several clubs that night and drunk a lot. When the last club was closing in the morning hours, he offered us a bed in his house. It was too late (or early) to knock on the door of our couchsurfer host and we decided to accept his invitation.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;A few hours later, we woke up with a terrible hangover, not remembering how we got there and wanted to go &amp;quot;home&amp;quot;. After a quick chat with our new friend, we decided to leave the house together and visit our host. We needed to leave before lunch time, as we cooked &amp;quot;goulash&amp;quot; for our host a day before, that still required two hours of cooking and some attention. We promised, we would eat it for lunch together with his family, so we were under time pressure.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;As we were walking out of Nikys house, he told us that he forgot something and if we can wait for him for a while. We sat down in the lobby and he disappeared to the kitchen. After fifteen minutes, we were getting nervous and hungry. Andrea went looking for him. He wasn&amp;#39;t in the house anymore and must have left through the garage or the back. We encountered only a small dog, barking hysterically at us.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;After thirty minutes, we decided to leave. We opened the entrance door and went to the gate, which was locked. We sat down again and waited. One hour passed and our mood shifted from angry to desperate. We were thinking of going through the back, but there was another big dog in the garden. Our next idea was to climb the fence, but that was impossible because the house was built like a fortress, with spikes on the fence.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;We were hungover, thirsty, hungry and trapped in a house of a person that we just met last night. A few conspiracy theories crossed our drunken minds. After a while a car parked in front of the house. Finally, our friend reappeared, it took him &amp;quot;only&amp;quot; 75 minutes. He told us that he had to pick up food for his father.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;We went to our CS host and finalized the Goulash, a Czechoslovak specialty. Our &amp;quot;kidnapper&amp;quot; asked, if we can save a bit for him. Igor winked at me and said in Slovak &amp;quot;Yeah but first we lock you up in here for an hour or two&amp;quot; :)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Lima is the capital of Peru. Tourists tend to skip Lima, because of its reputation as a dirty and dangerous city. We will try to convince you that it is worth to spend a couple of days. Lima has undoubtedly one of the best food scenes in South America. It has a very European vibe with cafes and restaurants on every corner. We were surprised, finding German style houses all over the city. It is a modern city, but the center maintains its colonial style.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Miraflores and Barranco were our favorite districts, packed with great restaurants, bars and music clubs. Because of the ocean and the Humboldt current, Lima has a moderate climate, often hazy and humid. The surfing conditions in Lima are good, but you need a full wet suit to enjoy the waves. Surfing schools along the beach offer courses and boards for affordable prices. We recommend to spend at least four days in Lima, to cover the most famous districts and to enjoy the food and the incredible pisco sours.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Lima from Huaraz&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are at least seven bus companies operating between Huaraz and Lima. We recommend to check regularly Cruz del Sur web page, as they have often promotions on specific destinations. Cruz del Sur is one of the oldest and superior bus companies.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;We asked for prices in several offices and in the end we chose Zbuss. We got seats in the lower floor, which is always better in Peru, because it is more spacious. The seats were adjustable to 160°, there was a toilet and TV, overall a very comfortable journey. It was an overnight bus and took about 8 hours and it cost us only 40 PEN p.p..&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museum Larco&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;One of the most organized and beautiful museums in SA. It is a private museum and with 30 PEN entrance the price is a bit higher compared to public museums, though it is worth it. Plan at least two hours for a tour. It is popular for its erotic exposition, a wide collection of erotic statues. Some of the figures are weird and pervert, like a woman having sex with a dead man and beating another man with a stick. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Museum Larco&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Museum Larco&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Museum Larco&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Museum Larco&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Museum Larco&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Museum Larco&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Mistura food festival&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This annual festival is the biggest food festival in South America. We were so lucky to be in Lima at this time (13.9.2015). Our favorite section was the sea food and ceviches. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We tried a Peruvian specialty, Anticuchos - barbecued beef hearts. The meat was tender and well seasoned. The stall was from restaurante Grimanesa (Felipe Barreda 475, Miraflores). &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;A pleasant surprise was &amp;quot;Asado de tira estofado en cerveza negra&amp;quot;, meat cooked with dark beer and mashed potatoes from restaurant Catalina 555. The meat was beautifully tender and aromatic from the beer.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/perucatalina&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Catalina 555&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Av. Santa Catalina 555, Lima&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We finished our food tour with a chiclayo and maracuya pisco from the famous Ayahuasca bar. Very good taste and strong. You can find this bar on Av. San Martin 130, Barranco.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We enjoyed the Grand Market, where farmers were presenting different local products like fruit, vegetables, chocolate, coffee, nuts, pisco and much more. We learned a lot about Peruvian food and its ingredients. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Lima Mistura&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Barranco Beer Company&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This brewery, located in the heart of Barranco, offers craft beers. You can choose from lager, weed beer, pale ale, amber beer, american IPA or brown beer. Their Pale-X was our favorite. You can order a tray with samples. Small beers cost about 8 PEN, big ones (600 ml) cost 15 PEN. They have also food, we didn&amp;#39;t try but the pizza on the next table looked good.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima14.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Barranco Beer Company&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Barranco Beer Company&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.barrancobeer.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Beer company&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Av Almirante Miguel Grau 308, Barranco&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Salchipapa&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You have to try salchipapas: fries covered with sausage chunks and different sauces. It is the perfect hangover food. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;La Lucha&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This fast food chain serves sandwiches. You can choose from baked pork (chancho a la lena), hamburger, pavo (grilled turkey) or beef. They have the best chicha morada ever! The sandwiches are out of this world. So are the fries, they use different kinds of potatoes, so you can find a red potato in your fries. The prices are ok, the sandwiches start at 13 PEN, fries (share in two, the portion is too big) 5 PEN, big chicha 4.50 PEN. La Lucha is a chain, later we found them also in Arequipa.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.lalucha.com.pe/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;La Lucha&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Av. Santa Cruz 747, Miraflores&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/lima/lima15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;La Lucha&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;La Lucha&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Lima has a good nightlife. You want get disappointed in Miraflores or Barranco. There are plenty of bars and clubs. We spent one crazy night in the clubs on Av. Bolognesi in Barranco, unfortunately we don&amp;#39;t remember the names of the bars, way too many beers and cocktails :) . &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Huaraz		</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/huaraz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/huaraz.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Andrea didn&amp;#39;t struggle with high altitude, so on the 3rd day of the Santa Cruz trek, she decided to do an extra hike to the Arhuaycocha glacier lake. Because we didn&amp;#39;t have enough time and energy, we didn&amp;#39;t do the Laguna 69 trek. We heard that it is a difficult one day hike, with a spectacular view of the Laguna. I didn&amp;#39;t want to miss the opportunity to see something similar. Our tourist guide told us the directions and made sure that we won&amp;#39;t get lost. She had to stay with the rest of the group, which headed directly to the camp for the night. We were told that the extra hike takes at least three hours, plus the hike to the camp five hours. The lake and the view around were amazing. I saw chunks of ice from the glacier falling into the turquoise crystal clear water and snow covered mountain peaks. When we descended, we were amazed by a weired tree. The bark of the tree looked like layers of paper and you could peel it like an onion. We returned proudly from the extra trek and we headed to the camp. After a while the surrounding nature turned into a dessert. We took off our jackets and started to sweat. I finished my last bottle of water, thinking we are already close. The tourist guide told us that it is in the valley, so it has to be close. It wasn&amp;#39;t. Thanks god my fellow travelers were so kind to share water with me. After a while we finished all our water. The valley was very dry, windy and hot. We were having a break, when we spotted somebody coming towards us. We asked him about our camp and how far it is. The local answered that it is five hours more! The mood dropped a bit. Luckily one of the clever Spanish friends had purification drops to clean the river water. He wasn&amp;#39;t really sure if they work, as the river was polluted by cow and donkey fecal. In the end, we took the risk and drunk the treated river water and we survived! The camp was just two hours away. Don&amp;#39;t trust the locals about directions or durations, usually they exaggerate :)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Huaraz is a city located in the mountains of north-central Peru. Most of the city was destroyed in the seventies by an earthquake. The city is not pretty, but it is a good starting place for trekking. One of the most difficult and best things that we&amp;#39;ve done in our lives, was the Santa Cruz trek. Tourists come to Huaraz because of the mountain hikes and the national park Huascaran.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Huaraz from Mancora&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We left from Mancora. We wanted to save money and we chose a cheap bus company called Etti. Big mistake, this was the worst bus in South America. You can find offices of bus companies close to the market. Cruz del Sur is probably the most expensive and most comfortable. We paid 70 PEN p.p. with Etti to get to Casma. From Casma it&amp;#39;s additional four hours to Huaraz, with another bus for 20 PEN.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Cruz del Sur asked 100 PEN from Mancora to Trujillo. From Trujillo we would have to travel another 8 hours.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can choose from many treks, from half a day to 15 days long trek. There are plenty of agencies to choose from, with different levels of services. If you are experienced, you can go on your own. You only need to pay the entrance fee of 65 PEN valid for 21 days.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Santa Cruz trek&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We asked around in a few companies about the prices and the equipment. In the end, we trusted our hostel manager and we booked a trip through him (Brujula Travel). The cost for the four days and three nights trek was 120 USD. The price included: &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;food, three times per day (breakfasts, picnic and dinner)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;water from the second day of the trek&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;tent and a sleeping back&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;transportation of food and equipment by donkeys&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;minibus transport to and from the national park&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;experienced tourist guide&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The entrance fee of 65 PEN to the park is not included in the price. The tour operators need a couple of days to gather enough people for a tour, so you might wait a few days. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Day 1&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The first day is very easy. They picked us up at 6:30 am and we spent next six hours in a car. Around two hours later we made a stop in a small village and we had breakfast (not included in the price). We arrived at the park entrance and payed the fee of 65 PEN. The car took us further into the park. We arrived in a small village where we met up with our donkeys. Then we walked about four hours along a flat path to the first camp. We built our tents, ate a dinner and went to sleep. We were 3400m above see level. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Day2&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The second day was the most difficult day. We woke up at 5:30 and after a breakfast, we started the eight hours long uphill hike. Four out of ten people were struggling with high altitude sickness. The first part of the trek wasn&amp;#39;t that spectacular. But then after a steep and exhausting ascend, we were rewarded with this amazing views:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Day 3&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On the third day, we were mostly descending. It took 6 hours, or 9 hours including an extra hike to the lake. The nature was becoming more dry and rocky as we continued to our camp. On the way, we encountered yet another emerald colored lake. Then, a river appeared in front of us and the nature became again more inviting and lush. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Day4&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The last day of the hike took us along the river. It was a very steep and rocky, downhill path. It took us around 3 hours to a village, where the bus was waiting for us. We arrived in Huaraz around 2pm. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Willkawain&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is a nice one day trip, that you can do on your own. There are busetas and taxis going to Wilkawain and El Pinar. We wanted to adjust to the high altitude, so we decided to hike there. We got lost a few times, because there are no direction signs.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;First we went to El Pinar. From there you have some nice views of the city and the surrounding mountains. El Pinar is actually a small neighborhood surrounded by fences. It is home to the miners and their families. It looked like a ghost city because nobody was there.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;When you turn your back to the entrance of El Pinar you have two options to choose from. One road leads back to Huaraz. The road to the left leads to Willkawain. On the first crossroad turn left. This small path will take you to Willkawain. The entrance fee to Willkawain is 5 PEN. This ruins are from the Wari empire. It used to be a large rural settlement of 5 square kilometers. The best preserved are the &amp;quot;Chullpas&amp;quot;, structures of one or more floors, specially constructed to house the corpses of one or more individuals of the elite class. Next to the Chullpas were constructions and houses, where people normally lived and conducted their daily labors... pretty morbid. To return to Huaraz you can take a minibus for 2.50 PEN.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Market&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The inside of the market is not that interesting, usually they serve soups and meat that you can get everywhere else. The more interesting things are outside the market, where merchants sell pork sandwiches or &amp;quot;Ceviche de chocho&amp;quot;. Ceviche de chocho is a kind of bean, seasoned with lime, chili peppers, tomatoes and onion. Surprisingly good and it costs only 1 PEN. Peruvians eat it for breakfast. The pork sandwich was phenomenal, so juicy and full of flavors. In the small side streets around the market are many &amp;quot;fruterias&amp;quot; which prepare fresh juices and fruit salads. Our favorite was &amp;quot;Jugueria Margarita&amp;quot; at Jose de la Mar 467.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;El Tio Enrique&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Craving a sausage or beer? The sausages are delicious and this restaurant offers a vast variety of Peruvian and European beers. They have Italian, Swiss or German sausage and they serve Sierra Andina, which is really good local beer. We had two sausages and two beers and we paid 42 PEN. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/eltioenriquehz&amp;quot;&amp;gt;El Tio Enrique&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Simon Bolivar 580, opens from 5 pm.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;La Brasa Roja&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you are really hungry or you want to share a portion. Their specialty is the roasted chicken with fries, salad and sauces. The chicken was tender and juicy, the fries were also good. Tell them you want the fries &amp;quot;bien fritos&amp;quot;, otherwise you will get the usual SA fries, white and not crispy. They make a very good chicha morada. Chicha morada is a drink from purple corn with cinnamon and other spices. The chicken comes with different sauces like ketchup, tartar sauce, olive sauce and aji (a chili sauce). For two quarters of chicken with fries and two chichas, we paid 40 PEN. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.labrasarojaperu.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;La Brasa Roja&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Luzuriaga 915&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The restaurant next to El Rinconcito Minero&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This restaurant is just next doors to the right from El Rinconcito. They don&amp;#39;t have any info on the Internet and we forgot the name of the restaurant. If you want to try Peruvian food visit this restaurant. The Ceviche was perfect and we tried also Papa a la Huancaina. The papa is very popular in Ancash, it is a potato with a delicious creamy sauce. Next we ordered Lomo Saltado, the most traditional meal after ceviche. It&amp;#39;s basically beef stripes with chunks of tomatoes, onions and bell peppers, with smoky flavor and sauce from the meat. They serve menu del dia for 15 PEN. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Julian Morales 757&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz14.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/huaraz/huaraz15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Huaraz&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Ezama hostel&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;A cheap hostel managed by the kind owner Emilio is located a bit further outside. Around 15 minutes walking from the center. We had a double room with private bathroom for 50 PEN per night. Emilio helped us with the Santa Cruz trek and we were very happy with the service. The only downside was, that we had to tell them to turn on the boiler before we took a shower. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://ezamahuaraz.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Ezama hostel&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Mancora</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/mancora.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/mancora.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We have just arrived to this beach town and we wanted to try some street food. We crossed the town two times and we couldn&amp;#39;t find anything. On the end, at dawn, we found one woman cooking meat and rice... very innovative.&amp;quot;What the heck, let&amp;#39;s try it&amp;quot;. We ordered two plates and we were... not pleased with the flavor. An older man, smoking his cigarette, obviously not Peruvian noticed it. He came closer and asked how our food was. We said that not so good but that it is fine. He started to laugh and told us stories, how the locals sometimes cook rats, cats and donkeys. That killed our appetite for good and we fed the rest of the food to stray dogs.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The positive side effect of meeting him was, that he introduced us to Coco, a very good surfing instructor. Next day, we went into the waves, doing our best to stand up on a board for the first time. Coco helped us to get to the right place, where we could catch the wave. Even when we were in the water on our own, not paying him, he was helping us a lot. When we saw other instructors, we were very happy to have Coco. From what we could observe, other instructors were not that attentive. Conclusion? We maybe ate the most disgusting food ever, but it helped us to connect with Coco and have one of the best times on our trip. So people, step out of your comfort zone, eat disgusting food and talk to drunk old strangers without prejudice. It could lead you to life changing moments. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This was one of our favorite places in Peru. Because of the ocean, surfing, really friendly people, warm water and the perfect weather. Mancora is almost always sunny and the average temperature is about 27 degrees. Montanita which is 500 km away, is often cloudy and rainy. We weren&amp;#39;t happy with the weather in Montanita at all. Other travelers told us that the weather in Peru is better. They were definitely right. The only disadvantage is that the nightlife is not as good as in Montanita.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;This hippie village is located in the north of Peru. We read on the internet, that Mancora is expensive. Maybe that would be true, if you would eat only in expensive restaurants and live in exclusive hotels. Truth is, that you can find very cheap hostels and menu del dia in every restaurant. To lower your expenses, you should definitely bargain for services. Especially with moto taxis, they ask tourists for double or even triple prices. We liked this place a lot and we spent one week in a very nice hostel called Kon Tiki. This is the right place, to take a vacation from your vacation and rest during your long term traveling.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;You can watch Iguanas in Mancora. They are well hidden behind the handcraft market in the bushes. If you throw them pieces of bananas, they will come out of the bushes. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Mancora&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We took a night bus from Cuenca directly to Mancora and we crossed the borders to Peru. Don&amp;#39;t worry about crossing the border at night, it was completely safe and very quick. We left Cuenca at 9:00 pm and we were at Mancora 4:30 am the next day. It cost us 15 USD p.p..&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Water sports&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The beach in Mancora doesn&amp;#39;t have the best conditions for surfing. There is one spot, not large, where you can catch a wave. Obviously everyone is there and it can get crowded. Around Mancora are several, less frequented beaches where you can also surf or kite surf. Lobitos should have excellent surfing conditions, but be aware that you need a wet suite, as the water is really cold. There is a different, colder current south of Cabo Blanco (just 35 km south from Mancora), the Humboldt current. Because of the stable and very strong winds, it is a kite surfers paradise. Kite surfing is not so popular yet, so you have a lot of space.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;We took surfing lessons with Coco. Unfortunately we forgot the name of the school. You can find the school on the beach boulevard. Just ask around the beach for Coco the surf instructor. For 50 PEN (15 USD) you get a two hours lesson, including wet suit and the board which you can keep for rest of the day. They also rent surf boards incl. wet suit for 20 PEN a day.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.vivamancora.com/english/surf.htm&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.vivamancora.com/english/surf.htm&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Swimming with sea turtles&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are many tourist agencies selling this trip for 90 PEN or more. It is possible to do it on your own, for 42 PEN for two people. Take a bus from the bus terminal to Organos and then a moto taxi to Nuro. The bus costs 2 PEN p.p. one way, the moto taxi 10 PEN each way. To get to the turtles, you have to pay the entrance to the peer, which costs only 5 PEN. They are feeding them, so they come close. They are used to people. You can jump into the water and swim with them. Andrea rented snorkels for 5 PEN. You should avoid touching the turtles, which is almost impossible, as they swim so close to you that they are touching you all the time. An absolutely unique experience. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Exploring surrounding beaches&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are alternatives to the Mancora beach in the surrounding. Like the Pocitas beach, 5 km south of Mancora. It was our favorite. A moto taxi will take you there for 5 PEN. We were there in winter and we had the beach for ourselves. The sand is very fine and water is clean. There are no bars nor shops, so bring food and water. The waves can get strong and big. We had so much fun jumping into them, we were like kids. Stay till the sun set, it is spectacular. If you are lucky and patient, you can spot wales jumping on the horizon. The season for whales is from June until October.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Further south are for example Organos or Cabo Blanco beaches. We visited Organos (take the bus from terminal for 2 PEN). The beach was dirty, so we didn&amp;#39;t stay long. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;La Gran Piadina&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This was our favorite restaurant in Mancora. We came for menu del dia almost every day. We tried everything on the menu. For 15 PEN you get a salad or bread with garlic, main course and a juice. Everything was always fresh and delicious. We loved their tuna steak with spaghetti al pesto or crispy chicken with mashed potatoes. Really good seasoned, tasty food. They open from 12 o&amp;#39;clock till 22:00.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora La Gran Piadina&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora La Gran Piadina&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora La Gran Piadina&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora La Gran Piadina&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/Lagranpiadinamancora2013&amp;quot;&amp;gt;La Gran Piadina&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Av. Piura 245&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Bananas cafe&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This place is perfect for good and cheap breakfast. They have sandwiches, eggs and even a salad with cheese. We liked Bananas combo breakfast, which consists of a salad: piece of avocado, tomatoes, cheese and focaccia with olive oil; small yogurt with fruits and granola, fresh juice and coffee or tea for 10 PEN. Continental costs 6 PEN. Adress:Av. Piura 224&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.vivamancora.com/bananascafe/#_=_&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Bananas cafe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Market&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want good and fresh ceviche, visit the market during the day. There are five or six stalls next to each other, serving this Peruvian specialty. We tried the one with black mussels &amp;quot;conchas negras&amp;quot;. It was one of the best ceviches, that we&amp;#39;ve tried in Peru. They serve it with a sweet potato, steamed corn and crunchy fried corn. Costs 15 PEN.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora Market&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora Market&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora Market&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora Market&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Kon Tiki hostel&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This hostel is on the small hill in Mancora, overlooking the sea and the city. Far enough from the smog and noise. They offer bungalows. We chose the cheapest option for 35 PEN for a double room with shared bathroom. The bathroom was always clean, the shower strong enough and the WiFi good. The advantage of a bungalow is, that you have privacy, a terrace and a hammock. We spent the afternoons reading books, drinking beer and looking at the sea from our gorgeous view point. You can use the kitchen and a big social area with sofas, tables and chairs. We stayed one week. If we come back to Mancora, we would stay again in this hostel. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora Kon Tiki&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora Kon Tiki&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora Kon Tiki&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora Kon Tiki&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora Kon Tiki&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora Kon Tiki&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;During the week, there is not much going on. On weekends, the beach bars pull out the speakers and play very loud music. Very bad commercial music usually. However young people from Mancora are very nice, friendly and open minded. They like to talk to tourists and share beers. On the end we didn&amp;#39;t care that they play shitty music, we danced under the stars with legs soaking in sea water and had fun with nice people. Atelier club, av. Piura, plays house or techno music regularly. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora14.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora sun set&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora sun set&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/mancora/mancora15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mancora sun set&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mancora sun set&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cuenca</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/cuenca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/cuenca.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We came to Cuenca to visit the beautiful natural park of El Cajas. As usual we didn&amp;#39;t want to go with a tourist guide. We came to the entrance office to get a map. Unfortunately they didn&amp;#39;t have any printed maps, so we took a few pictures of the map on the wall. You can choose from very easy to difficult level of hiking paths. We decided to do the moderate hike, that would take us five hours. There was a group of German tourists deciding which trail to take. The guides from the office told us to stay together as a group, as the park is really big and its easy to get lost. They called a car to take us to the beginning of the hike. We told to the driver which hike we chose. We were very surprised when he drove off to the opposite direction. We were thinking that perhaps he knows a better way. We were surprised when he took us to the easiest path. We explained to him that we are at the wrong place and we would have to ascend for the whole day to get to the right path. He was totally lost, he called the office and brought us to another point and almost left. When we found out that this trail is also not the right one, we stopped him again and jumped in the car for the last time. Finally, after showing him pictures of the map, he drove us to the right place. A funny moment was when Igor told us that he had noticed that our driver had a driving license test book on his side and was learning from it. Welcome to Ecuador, the country where anybody can do anything! :)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The beautiful historic city of Cuenca is located 2.500m above sea level. The city center is listed as UNESCO World Heritage Site. It has a charming atmosphere of the old times and a good food scene. Many people skip this city, because they&amp;#39;ve visited Quito. We like Cuenca more then Quito and not just because of the food. We liked the vibe and the city was also pretty clean. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Cuenca&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We went from Puerto Lopez (close to Montanita) to Guayaquil for 5.25 USD. The bus from Guayaquil to Cuenca costs 8.25 USD. It was a long day in buses, but it brought us closer to the borders with Peru.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;El Cajas&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This national park is located 30 km from Cuenca, between 3.000 meters up to 4.500 meters. You can find more then 200 lagoons in a pure, unspoiled nature. The weather can change very fast so bring enough warm clothes. You don&amp;#39;t need any tourist guide to explore the park. There are buses leaving in the morning from Cuenca.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Take a bus from Presidente Cordova, the street located in the city center, to the market Feria Libre. The ride takes about twenty minutes. From there follow the street in the direction of the bus and after a big modern bus station (and before a supermarket) immediately turn right. You should see a Occidental sign on a lamp post. Follow the sign and after fifty meters you will find their office on the left. The ticket costs 2.25 USD one way. We took the bus at 8:30, but there are also earlier buses. The journey to the Toreadora lake, the main entrance of the park, takes about one hour. You have to pay a fee of 2 USD for the entrance. You can choose from fifteen trails. We took the blue one, difficulty moderate. The trail wasn&amp;#39;t difficult. Sometimes we had troubles to find the marks. It is possible to camp there. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://parque-nacional-cajas.org/tracks.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;El Cajas&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-xs-12 col-md-8 carousel&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/las_cajas1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/las_cajas2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/las_cajas3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/las_cajas4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/las_cajas5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/las_cajas6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Pumapungo museum&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We liked this museum mainly because of the outdoor part. There are archaeological excavations with a mock of an Inca garden and the characteristic terraces. You can find corn, quinoa, yucca, papas, kiwicha or chili peppers and find out more about the Inca diet. The Incas planted herbs and domesticated animals like parrots or lizards. What we didn&amp;#39;t like at all was the exposition of parrots and even eagles and a condor in very small cages. Big shame on you, museum Pumapungo...&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The main building houses different expositions. We enjoyed the one dedicated to modern art on the ground floor. On the upper floor is an ethnological exposition which is very disorganized and poorly presented. The entrance is for free.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-xs-12 col-md-8 carousel&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/pumapungo8.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Here you can find the address and opening hours:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.museos.gob.ec/redmuseos/index.php/museos/itemnucleares/itempumapungo&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Museo Pumango&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Historic city center&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can spend easily hours browsing the old town. Exploring churches, narrow streets and cozy cafeterias. The colonial city was founded in 1557. The city has 52 churches, one for every Sunday. Walk down to the river Tomebamba and sit next to the locals and absorb the atmosphere. The city is very photogenic especially at dawn. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-xs-12 col-md-8 carousel&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Restaurante Trastevere&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After eating rice for two months, we felt the urge to eat European food. We chose a cozy Italian restaurant, close to our hostel. This restaurant attracted us with wide selection of italian cheese and homemade pasta. We ordered a plate with sausages, cheese and homemade bread as a starter. The main course was pasta, ravioli and red wine. Everything was delicious and fresh. The young waiter was a bit chaotic, but all in all we were very pleased and satisfied. We paid 50 USD with tips included.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/Gastronomiaitalianacuenca/#_=_&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Restaurante Trastever&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Honorato Vasquez 6-26&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Waffles de Belgica&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is a small buffet in the park close to Pumapungo. The Belgium chef will make a fresh waffle in front of you. You choose fruits, ice cream and topping. The price is about 2 USD for a waffle.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/wafflesBelgica#_=_&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Waffles de Belgica&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Av. 3 de Noviembre&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Tutto Fredo&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can find this cafeteria also in Latacunga. The place is very popular with locals and you can choose from wide selection of ice creams, cakes and sandwiches. We liked the brownie with ice cream and cappuccino. The sandwich was disappointing. This is a good and cheap place for afternoon coffee and cake. It is located in the city center right at the main square Abdon Calderon.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;The Market&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This market was one of the cleanest we have seen in South America. In the third floor is comida rapida, alias fast food. They have pork, with pork and pork... As a side dish they serve corn. If you like to cook, check the meat section. It looked very fresh and good. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cuenca/cuenca8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cuenca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Hostel Alvanos&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We stayed here for three nights and we were very happy. The room was spacious and bright. The hostel was very clean. It is located in the city center, very close to restaurants and bars. It is a bit annoying that you have to ring every time you want to enter the hotel. We paid 20 USD per night for a double room. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.alvanoshostal.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Alvanos&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Honorato Vásquez, Cuenca 010103, Ecuador&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Montanita &amp; Isla de la Plata</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/montanita.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/montanita.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/montanita_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After the never ending 10 hours ride on a bus, we got off in the hippie village of Montanita. We booked our hostel in advance on Hostelworld, because we knew that we will be tired after this long journey. Little did we know, what a big fail it will be. At the bus stop was a line of hostel employees to offer us accommodation for less money and/or in better location. We rejected all the offers. One sympathetic guy with French accent approached us and asked about our hostel. When we said that it is located in the center, he just laughed and said that we won&amp;#39;t get any sleep in the night. And we were like, &amp;quot;Ehm sure, what ever. We are used to it from parties&amp;quot;. We found our hostel and the manager. The twenty something surfer with blond dreadlocks opened the door to our room and a terrible chemical smell punched into our noses. We were thinking, maybe someone used a lot of mosquito repellent in there. We lied down into our bunk beds, in a room without a window. After two hours Andrea got a terrible headache and both of us would still smell the chemical odor. We realized that the smell was coming from the freshly painted walls. We couldn&amp;#39;t find the manager to confront him, so we packed and went out to search for Nicos hostel, our French connection. Luckily he had a private room for us. Sitting in the lounge area in Nicos hostel ChiChi Babylon, we glanced at the white board with the house rules: &amp;quot;Rule No. 6: In here we fuck Hostelworld with a big smile&amp;quot;, which made us laugh. Now writing this article, we have a second laugh, as we have just discovered that Nico&amp;#39;s hostel is listed on Hostelworld.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Montanita is a small hippie town on the Ecuadorian coast with perfect conditions for surfing. It has great nightlife and a nice beach. The only downside is that the weather is very often cloudy and there are lot of mosquitoes. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Montanita, Ecuador&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We went from Banos through Guayaquil. Buy the ticket one day in advance if you want to travel early in the morning, it costs around 10 USD. Ask them also from where the bus leaves, because some of the companies stop in front of the terminal. They didn&amp;#39;t tell us and we missed our bus. Luckily it was not our fault and several other tourists missed the bus. They arranged a different bus for us which was not direct and it was a lot of trouble... On Guayaquil&amp;#39;s bus terminal (is also a shopping mall and airport) buy a ticket to Montanita. There is just one office selling them. It&amp;#39;s 6 USD. This journey took us the whole day, we got up at 5:30 am and arrived at 5 pm. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Surfing lessons&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The waves here are very strong, long and consistent. They host many international competitions. You can choose from many surfing schools or take a private teacher. Igor took one lesson 1.5 hour for 20 USD. He was very happy with the teacher. The jelly fish was annoying, but that&amp;#39;s pretty common here. If you decide to stay in ChiChi Babylon, ask Nico the owner about the lessons, he will point you to the right teacher. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cabana I Ciuchi&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This restaurant moved from the beach to the center on Calle 15 Mayo. They serve sea food and international meals. We absolutely loved the langostinos. It&amp;#39;s not a cheap restaurant, prices begin on 12 USD. If you want something cheaper try &amp;quot;Brisa Sabores Peruanos&amp;quot;. They are on the same street. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/montanita1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;CabanaICiuchi&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;CabanaICiuchi&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/montanita2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;CabanaICiuchi&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;CabanaICiuchi&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Pigro&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Italian restaurant serving pasta and sea food. They have happy hours for cocktails. Try their pasta with &amp;quot;mariscos&amp;quot; sea food, it&amp;#39;s absolutely amazing. This is not a budget restaurant, a dish is about 15 USD. It is located on calle Publica y 10. Agosto. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;ChiChi Babylone&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This hostel is located by the river, just five minutes walk from the beach. The atmosphere is very social. There is a TV with Netflix, couches and hammocks in the garden. We met very nice people from UK, Australia and Belgium. We talked, laughed, drunk cheap and good ron every night and went out to party. We appreciated that we could socialize and have fun. In the night it was usually quiet and we had no troubles to sleep. You can use the kitchen and buy beers from Nico. First two nights we slept in the double room. The bed has a mosquito net and bathroom is just next door. Then we slept three nights in a dormitory with four people, no mosquito net and with a bathroom next doors. With really hot water and very fast wi-fi for 8 USD per person it is a very good deal.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There is a lot to do during the whole week but the weekends are more interesting. The cocktail alley is a street full of stands serving hundreds of different cocktails. Seriously we haven&amp;#39;t ever seen such a wide selection.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;There are several night clubs in Montanita. From salsa discos, rock to electronic music. Some places are really weird, like Alcatraz a 3 floor disco that looks like a prison. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Lost Beach club&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The best place where to party is Lost Beach club. It&amp;#39;s opened just on weekends, so check their website for events. They have a Function One sound system and pretty large space outside where you can dance under the night sky and a dance floor inside. They host regularly international artists, like Joyce Muniz, Bushwacka or Marcel Fengler from Ostgut Ton label. We visited the club Friday and Saturday. On Fridays they have ladies nights, so ladies don&amp;#39;t pay entrance. On Saturdays they have more interesting events. We enjoyed the set from Francesca Lombardi and Agents of Time. The after party was on the inside stage until Sunday noon. It is for sure one of the best clubs in South America!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.lostbeachclub.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lost beach club&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/joytoy&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Joyce Muniz&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Isla de la Plata&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This small island belongs to the natural park Machalilla. It is also called the poor man&amp;#39;s Galapagos, because of the rich wildlife and the cheap price of the tour. If you want to visit the island you have to book a tour. The tours start from Puerto Lopez, a small fisherman town located two hours bus drive from Montanita (2.50 USD). It is hard to find a hostel for 10 USD per night and the food is expensive and not very good. We heard that you can find tours for 30 USD. We tried to bargain, but the lowest price that we reached was 40 USD. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On the end, we booked the tour with a reliable company Aventuras la Plata for 45 USD and we think that the higher price was influenced by the whale watching season. They picked us up in our hostel, the boat was good and new. Sandwiches and fruits were included. We started very early in the morning, the boat ride takes about one hour. A guide will accompany the group of 4-16 persons and will explain a lot about the island at its animal inhabitants. First you will have to walk a path up to the summit of the island where the birds are nesting. You will run into the blue footed boobies, which sit on the ground along the walking paths. They are one of the funniest animals ever, we could spend hours watching them. Most of the time they reside in pairs, male and female. The male is smaller, the female bigger and with bigger eye pupils. You can also distinguish them by the different sounds they make. It is fun to watch them performing their mating dance, when they lift their feet up and down. Their significant blue feet turn darker blueish with age.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Frigatebird are also home on Isla de la Plata. The male birds have a significant red pouch. They inflate the pouch like a red balloon in the mating ceremony. The wingspan of this birds can reach up to 3 meters. Unlike the blue footed boobies the frigatebird can not dive to catch fish. Therefore, they chase and pick on the boobies to steal their prey. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Second part of the tour was on the boat. We saw giant sea turtles and fed them with bread and fruits. They are probably used to it, because they weren&amp;#39;t afraid at all and they came very close to the boat. Then we had half an hour for snorkeling, but that was very difficult because of jelly fish. Anyway, we saw beautiful colored fishes. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On the last part of the tour, we headed back and watched the whales. One of the most beautiful moment in our lives. We appreciated that the captain was respectful and each time we spotted a whale, he stopped the engine and told us to be quiet to not bother the animals. That day was very cloudy so the pictures are not the most beautiful ones, but we were so happy to see them. It increased our love and respect to the nature even more. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-xs-12 col-md-8 carousel&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata8.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/montanita/isladelaplata7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Banos</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/banos.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 2 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/banos.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On our first day in Banos, we decided to rent a buggy and explore the area. In the office they recommended us to visit the waterfalls. We were very excited about the trip, so we jumped right into the buggy and went for a ride. We passed by two beautiful waterfalls. Each time we parked our rented buggy, made some pictures, started the engine again and left. That wasn&amp;#39;t the case when we visited the fourth waterfall. We got into a line of cars passing underneath the waterfall and we couldn&amp;#39;t get back or park it. The only way is to go through the waterfall. We got a serious splash of water which was fun. Totally wet but happy we drove off to watch people doing bungee jumping from a bridge. We parked and shot some pictures, but then we realized that our three hours rent will be soon over and still we haven&amp;#39;t seen Pailon del Diablo, the biggest waterfall. So we went back to our buggy, turned the key... and nothing happened. Obviously the water got into the motor starter. Thanks god, some nice guy appeared and showed us how to start by shortcutting the starter in the back with a piece of metal. Because Igor was driving he taught me (Andrea) how to do it. Each time when we wanted to start, I had to open the lid of the starter and do the trick, which raised the attention of the locals, watching us with curiosity. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Banos&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Banos&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Banos - the bathroom of Ecuador. The city is located in the center of Ecuador at the foot of the Tungurahua volcano. It is popular with tourists because of the variety of adrenalin sports. You can do kayaking, zip lining, rafting, cycling, bungee jumping, rent a buggy, ATV or motorcycle. You can also explore the close volcano or the famous &amp;quot;Swing at the End of the World&amp;quot; at Casa del Arbol. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Banos&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Banos&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Banos&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We went to Banos after visiting Cotopaxi volcano, near Latacunga. In this case you have to go trough Ambato, the bus ticket costs 1.50 USD. From Ambato to Banos the bus costs 1.15 USD. The journey takes at least about three hours. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Banos&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Banos&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Waterfalls&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are about 14 waterfalls in Banos to explore, many of them very high. As we described above, we rented a buggy in Banos and we&amp;#39;ve seen four of them. We were pushed by the three hours renting time, which cost us 45 USD. We wanted to rent it for the whole day, but this was the maximum. All companies have the same prices and they are not keen to give discounts, but try anyway. They gave us a map of &amp;quot;Ruta de las Cascadas&amp;quot;, the map of waterfalls. Until the Pailon del Diablo you drive on the main road, along the River Pastaza, direction to Puyo city. There are signs for each waterfall. First we saw the small waterfall Agoyan. We continued to the waterfalls of Manto de la Novia. Very impressive, you can use the zip line cabin to get across and see it from closer distance. The most amazing and powerful waterfall is Pailon del Diablo. The entrance is 1.50 USD, for so little money you can get close and even behind the waterfall, shower included. We saw rainbows as well, really spectacular and not to be missed in Banos! &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-xs-12 col-md-8 carousel&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Zip lining&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are many places to do zip lining in Banos and we did a lot of research on it. We chose the&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Imagine Ecuador&amp;quot; travel agency. They offer zip lining in Puntzan, one of the longest in Banos. We really liked, that you had to do small hikes between the 6 zip lining tracks. On each zip line you try different styles like superman, upside down or sitting. If you are a couple or with a friend, you will appreciate the tandem zip line. It is a cool experience, as you can see in our youtube video. It costs 20 USD p.p. and includes the transport. This was definitely one of our favorite attractions in South America.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Zip lining Banos&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Zip lining Banos&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;iframe width=&amp;quot;420&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;315&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G0E65dH5e3A&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Hot springs&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After a long, adventurous day, we appreciated the hot springs. There are a dozen luxurious places that you can choose from, but the cheapest and most common option is to use the public spa. &amp;quot;Las Piscinas de La Virgen&amp;quot; spa is located close to the city center, to the left of the big waterfall. They are open early in the morning from 5 am till 5 pm and in the evening from 6 pm. The entrance fee is 3 USD. There are two levels. On the ground floor is a hot pool (around 40 degrees). On the second floor is a warm pool and larger cold pool. You can also have a shower in the waterfall, very cool. The warm pool is always packed, you can barely move. We spent most of the time in the hot pool, sitting on the edge of the pool with legs dipped in the water. You must wear a silly swimming cap. You can buy them on the way to the spa, from one of the local merchants. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/banos/banos9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Hot springs Banos&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Hot springs Banos&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Banos is a small, touristic city and the quality of the local restaurants was a bit of a disappointment. But there are some good options, which we would like to point out to you.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Market&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Eating on the local market is always a good option. We had the best Encebollado soup for 2.50 USD. We tried a local specialty &amp;quot;Yahuarlocro&amp;quot;, a soup from potatoes, meat and blood. Also delicious was &amp;quot;Llapingachos&amp;quot; (3 USD), a simple meal that consists of potato tortillas, chorizo, eggs, avocado, salad and of course the ever present rice:) Try fresh juice at the juice stalls from &amp;quot;zanahoria y manzana&amp;quot; carrot and apple, it&amp;#39;s cheap and good for your hangover. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Carpe Diem di Verdi&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the only restaurant that we can really recommend in Banos. They bake good pizza and calzone. The taste of the pastry was close to what we are used to from Europe. With 2 USD for a slice of pizza or empanada, it&amp;#39;s a bargain. Only downside was, that it had closed twice we went for dinner and lunch. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/CARPE-DIEM-DI-VERDI-425676664253463&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Carpe Diem di Verdi&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Hostal Cañalimeña&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We were satisfied with this hostel. For 20 USD, we got a nice double room with a private bathroom, hot water, comfortable bed, TV and fast internet. The location is 5 minutes walking distance from the center and far from the loud bars and discos. The staff is very nice and helpful. There is a kitchen that can be used by guests.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.hostalcanalimena.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Hostal Cañalimeña&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Latacunga &amp; Cotopaxi volcano &amp; Quilotoa lake</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/latacunga.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/latacunga.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/latacunga_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We booked a downhill mountain bike tour from the Cotopaxi volcano in our Hotel. The next morning a guide with a jeep picked us up. We asked where the bikes are. To his surprise he assumed we want a walking tour. The receptionist confirmed that a mistake was made with our booking. To our relief, the guide managed to organize two mountain bikes. The guide drove us to the volcano to 4300m from where we hiked to the shelter &amp;quot;Refugio Jose Rivas&amp;quot; at 4864m. After a short picnic we descended back to the car to start the downhill biking. After a few meters it became obvious that it will be difficult. The terrain is very unstable and full of volcanic ash, the bikes were of mediocre quality, the brakes were insufficient. Every 200m we had to stop and give our wrists and hands a rest from the constant breaking. We felt like riding wild horses and not bicycles, because they were so uncontrollable. Andrea was swearing and shouting like a warrior going to battle. One could have a good laugh watching us fight with our bicycles. The best part of the mountain bike tour was &amp;quot;encebollado&amp;quot;, a fish soup at the end.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cotopaxi volcano tour&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cotopaxi volcano tour&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Latacunga is a small town south of Quito in central Ecuador. It is a good starting point for the Cotopaxi volcano and the Quilotoa laguna. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Latacunga from Quito&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take a bus or trolleybus to &amp;quot;Estación Terminal Sur en Bus - El Recreo&amp;quot;, where you need to change to a bus that takes you to &amp;quot;Terminal Terrestre Quitumbe&amp;quot;. All buses cost 0.25 USD for a single route and you can use multiple buses, provided you don&amp;#39;t leave the terminal/station. The bus from Terminal Quitumbe to Latacunga costs 2.20 USD. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Quilotoa laguna&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Quilotoa is a beautiful blue crater laguna. You don&amp;#39;t have to book anything in advance. Take a bus from the terminal in Latacunga for 2.50 USD. You should leave from Latacunga 8-9 am to have enough time for the hike. The bus ride takes 2 hours. For a better acclimatization, we recommend to do the Quilotoa hike before you go to Cotopaxi.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;At Quilotoa you have to register and pay an entrance fee of 2 USD. You can visit a small indoor handcraft market there. It might be windy and cold on top of the crater, but once you start descending down to the lake, it will get warmer. The path down to the lake is slippery and full of ash. It took us 20 - 30 minutes to descent to the lake. If you take food with you, this would be a perfect place for a picnic. Walking back takes longer, 60 - 90 minutes. You can rent a mule to take you back up. In any case, bring enough water.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;There is also the possibility to do a trek around the lake, with sleep overs in hostels in the surrounding villages.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/quilotoa1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/quilotoa2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/quilotoa3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/quilotoa5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/quilotoa4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/quilotoa6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
       
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cotopaxi volcano&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The receptionist in the Latacunga hostel, where we were staying, offered us a trip to Cotopaxi volcano including downhill biking and lunch for 50 USD. This is a normal price, but better is to do some research and find a reliable company. We read very good reviews about &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.bikingdutchman.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Biking Dutchman&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Like we mentioned above we weren&amp;#39;t happy with the downhill at all. The rest of the tour was fine. We weren&amp;#39;t lucky, because that day the volcano was covered in clouds. On the way to the volcano our guide informed us that the natural park used to be much bigger. Unfortunately the corrupted government sold a big part of the park to a wood logging company. They cut down the original vegetation and started to plant pine trees instead. This caused problems with water, as pine trees accumulate the water, which led to water shrinkages in the surrounding areas. On the way back we visited a museum that shows how climate changes influenced flora and fauna around the volcano. Before these changes, the nature was green and Cotopaxi was covered with lot more snow. Now everything is very dry and the wild horses living in the park are dying of hunger. There are hundreds of them, we loved to watch them. You can also visit other nearby volcanoes or a lagoon. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi8.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi9.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/cotopaxi10.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Market&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We love eating in markets, as the food is very fresh and you get a chance to taste local dishes for low prices. &amp;quot;Chancho&amp;quot;, roasted pig with corn and salad, is very popular in Ecuador. We paid 2.50 USD for a meal.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/latacunga/latacunga_food1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Chancho&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Chancho&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Nice cream &amp;amp;amp; tutto fredo&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is a good spot for breakfast and ice cream. We went there twice for American breakfast and we loved their &amp;quot;mora&amp;quot; juice and marmalades. Mora tastes like blackberry. The price for American breakfast (toast, marmalade, juice, coffee and eggs) is 2.75 USD.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Nice cream &amp;amp;amp; tutto fredo, Guayaquil y Sanchez de Orellana&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Latacunga hostel is located in the city center. They have dorms and private rooms. The hostel looks nice, but the showers were dirty and the water wasn&amp;#39;t really hot. We paid for a dorm, but in the end we were alone in the room. The room was cold at night, you can ask for an extra blanket. The Wi-Fi was ok. A dormitory bed costs 10 USD.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Quito &amp; Otavalo</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/quito.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/quito.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On our way to Quito we stopped in Otavalo to visit the biggest handcrafts market in Ecuador. As experienced travelers, we are aware that every additional weight in the backpack turns out to be very inconvenient. We did not plan to buy anything, but then we arrived at the market and our promises disappeared into thin air. The selection of colorful sweaters, scarves, caps, socks, gloves, hammocks, blankets simply overwhelmed us. The merchants were offering us products that we really did not intend to buy. We were amazed by the quality and the softness of the alpaca wool. One older lady dressed in traditional Ecuadorian dress offered us a king size hammock. We said no and we started to go away. Immediately the price went down and we started to hesitate and think that perhaps we could send it with a parcel back to Europe. After a confirmation from her that everyone is doing it this way and that the post office is just around the corner and Ecuador being a cheap country, we decided that we go for it. We simply could not resist this once in a lifetime offer. We negotiated the price for the hammock and as if it was not enough, we bought a large alpaca blanket to fill up the parcel. The post office was already closed, so we decided to send the parcel from Quito the very next day. The next day, we did some research and asked our couchsurfing host about the prices. Unfortunately the price for an untraceable package our size would be more then 100 USD. The DHL online calculator came up with even more ridiculous price of 800 USD. Igor is now carrying his king size hammock with wooden spreaders, like Jesus his cross and Andrea has filled up her 15 liter backpack extension with a soft alpaca blanket, making the backpack bigger then her. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/otavalo1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Otavalo market&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Otavalo market&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get to Quito&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In our previous post we wrote down, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/blog/2015/salento.html#from-colombia-to-ecuador&amp;quot;&amp;gt;how to get to Quito from Colombia via Ipiales and Otavalo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Quito is the capital of Ecuador and is the highest official capital city in the world (2850m). The historic city of Quito and Kraków were among the first World Cultural Heritage sites declared by UNESCO in 1978. Quito has one of the largest and least-altered historic centers in Panamerica.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The official currency in Ecuador is US dollar. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Getting around Quito is difficult, as there are no bus schedules nor maps on the bus stations. However you will see that Quito has a network of buses and trolleybuses. When we asked around for direction, people would send us in the opposite way. The prices for the taxis varied from 4 USD to 8 USD, depending on the drivers mood and taximeter fare. Buses are with 0.25 USD very cheap. We tried to take the bus as often as possible, checking the direction with GPS on our phones. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Quito&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Quito&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Teleferico to Cruz Loma&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Cruz Loma is a viewpoint on the east side of the Pichincha volcano above Quito (more then 3900m). The easiest way to get there, is to take a taxi from the center for about 4 USD. Tell the driver to take you to the entrance of Teleferico. The cable car costs 8.50 USD, return ticket. It can be windy and cold up there, better take a jacket with you. From the cable car station at the top, you can go for a hike all the way up to Pichincha. You can also rent a horse. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Quito Teleferico&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Quito Teleferico&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Free walking tour&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Tours are held Monday through Saturday and the meeting point is in the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.communityhostel.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Community Hostel&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in the city center. You must make a reservation in advance on their website. From our experience, taking a guided tour is the best introduction to a city. This was by far the best free walking tour we have ever taken. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ovi, our guide is an experienced, veteran guide and he is one of the reasons that makes the tour special. The tour starts at the close by market, where you will learn about various Ecuadorian fruits. The second floor of the market has a food court and your guide will point out the best places where and what to eat. You will have the chance to buy fresh juice for 2 USD. The tour continues into the historic city center where you will get lot of historic facts. You will cross different sites like the Plaza Grande, Iglesia de la Compania, Church of the Jesuits or Presidential Palace. In front of the Palace was a demonstration, demanding the investigation of journalists disappearances. We discussed topics like the past and current political situation and also the reason why the president doesn&amp;#39;t live in the Presidential Palace anymore. Along the tour you will get tips on where to eat and how to stay safe in the city. At the end of the tour you will be asked for tips, as on any other free walking tour. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.freewalkingtourecuador.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Free walking tour&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Basilica del Voto&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This Gothic basilica offers astonishing views over the city. The entrance is only 2 USD. Walk up the stairs in one of the towers in the front section. Cross over a narrow wooden path to the back tower and if you are brave enough, climb even further up in to the very top of the tower. The very last part gives you an adrenaline rush, as you have to climb a very steep and narrow ladder. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Basilica del Voto&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Basilica del Voto&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Otavalo market&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The market is located 2 hours bus drive from Quito. Don&amp;#39;t hesitate to bargain with the sellers. They offer very nice, high quality products from alpaca wool or leather. Andrea bought a beautiful hand bag from leather, that would cost more then hundred dollars in Europe, for 20 USD. Don&amp;#39;t make the same mistake as we did and don&amp;#39;t buy anything large, if you have months of travel ahead of you. It is not worth it, as the post service is very expensive. The market starts to close down between five and six. One last tip, if you continue to Peru, there is a smaller and cheaper market in Huaraz, Peru.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/otavalo2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Otavalo&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Otavalo&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is not easy to find good, inexpensive food in Quito. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Las Corvinas de &amp;quot;Don Jimmy&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can find this food stand in the central market of Quito. They specialize in fish and sea food. We ordered &amp;quot;corvina con ceviche mixto&amp;quot;. The portion was big enough to feed both of us and costs 5 USD. The meat of the fish was very tender and didn&amp;#39;t have any bones. Everything was very fresh and delicious. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Las-Corvinas-de-Don-Jimmy/315064218546492&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Las Corvinas de &amp;quot;Don Jimmy&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Night life&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the bars and clubs are located in Mariscal district. You must have an ID on you to enter the bars here.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Bandido brewing&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can find this nice brewery by the Community hostel. They have six beers on tap. We really liked their IPA. They open at four o&amp;#39;clock and you can enjoy their happy hours till seven (around 3.50 USD per beer). &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/quito/quito10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Bandido brewing&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Bandido brewing&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://bandidobrewing.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Bandido brewing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Chupitos bar&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This small bar serves all kinds of shots. The list is long and you would probably die of alcohol intoxication by trying even a tenth of it. You can choose from rum, vodka, tequila based shots combined with syrups, spices, juices and other alcohols. These are not cocktails.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/ChupitosBarQuito&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Chupitos bar&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Salento</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/salento.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/salento.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We were walking through the Cocora Valley making our way down from the exhausting trek. The views are astonishing, especially on the second half of the tour, where you get to see the whole valley with its palm trees and the surrounding mountains. We stop at a small view point to get some rest and to shoot pictures. Suddenly we see something moving in the bushes close by. A few seconds later a small bear like creature appears very close to us. It was more surprised then us, starring at us with disbelief. Shocked as it was it tried to run away, but it was so clumsy that it rolled down the hill a few meters back into the bushes. It had troubles to get on its feet, complaining audibly. We observed it a few seconds longer before it disappeared out of our sight. Later we learned that it was a coati (nasua), one of many animals that live in the area around Salento. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;How to get there&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take a bus for 41.000 COP from Medellin terminal sur, located nearby the airport. The road is going through serpentines and it can give your stomach a hard time. Half of the way is like a roller coaster ride, not the easiest bus ride if you have a hangover. The bus heads to Armenia, where you can take another bus to Salento. However, the exit to Salento is on the way, so by going to Armenia you would have to go part of the same way back. Rather ask the driver to drop you off on the exit to Salento. On the other side of the road is a small bus stop. Be there before 6:00pm and you will be fine. This part of Colombia is safe and as it happened, we arrived after sunset and there was no bus, so we had to hitchhike to Salento. It took us only 15 minutes to catch a pickup. We were lucky though, there was very little traffic.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Salento is a cute little town in central Colombia. Famous for its landscape and its coffee production. You can easily spend a week there, exploring and hiking the surrounding mountains. It&amp;#39;s very popular with backpackers, but there is not much to do after the sunset. A few small bars with pool tables and music, but thats pretty much it. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Colibri&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Colibri&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cocora valley&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;First you need to jump on one of the jeeps that leave from the main plaza every morning. The last ones are leaving at 9:30 and it costs 3.400 COP p.p.. The way takes about 30 minutes and the jeep will take you to the entrance of Cocora. You have a few hike possibilities from here, as you can find out on the information table with a map. We did the longer round trip hike, which takes 4-5 hours. First it will take you on a mud way around the fields. Then it gets more interesting as the path turns into the jungle, jumping over stones, crawling under branches and crossing several hanging bridges. After that we started to ascend to Finca Montana (2860m altitude). After a short rest, finally we started to descent to Cocora Valley. We shot 200 pictures of the valley, it is breath taking. Take your time, sit on the view points and make a picnic. This is our second favorite place in Colombia, after &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/tayrona.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tayrona&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;col-xs-12 col-md-8 carousel&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Horse riding&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ask around on the main square for &amp;quot;caballo&amp;quot; and expect to pay at least 20.000 COP p.p. for one hour. Our guide ask us, if we are experienced and when Andrea told him &amp;quot;un poco&amp;quot;, she got really wild big horse that wanted to run all the time. Thanks god, the guide switched the horse with her and she got a nice pony :) For Igor it was the first time riding a horse and he couldn&amp;#39;t choose any better then a horse that walked like on autopilot - refusing to take any orders from him:) Nice experience, we definitely want to do it again.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;To our surprise, you can find several good places to eat in this small town.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Parilla&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They have only grilled meat, nothing for vegetarians. We had pork ribs and a steak. The meat was very tender and the marinade for the ribs was amazing. Finally, after hundreds of plates with boring rice, a potato as side dish and nice salad! With two club Colombia beers we paid 38.000 COP, generous tip included. You can find this restaurant on Calle 5. From the main plaza, facing the church go right to the street that goes downhill. It&amp;#39;s second house on the left. It&amp;#39;s a new restaurant, so they don&amp;#39;t have website and unfortunately we don&amp;#39;t remember the name.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;American brunch&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The perfect place for hangover food. The portions are unbelievable, you can&amp;#39;t ever eat the whole portion. We had a burrito and hash browns. Everything was nice and tasty, but we absolutely loved the peanut butter brownie with vanilla ice cream. In other words, the brownie is a must have. The filtered coffee is ordinary, but you pay one cup and you get refills for free. Half of the burrito we took with us and ate it for dinner. So with 40.000 COP we covered the whole day. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;American brunch, Calle 6 No. 3-25&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cafe Jesus Martin&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;A very very good cafeteria that serves homemade cakes. We had a coffee cake and a red fruit cake. The coffee was one of the best that we&amp;#39;ve tasted in SA. The water for coffee is filtered and the enormous filter is placed visibly on the wall. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.cafejesusmartin.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Cafe Jesus Martin&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Carrera 6&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cafe Bernabe Gourmet&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Nice option for fine dining in Salento. A little bit more expensive, but after long time of backpacking you want to treat yourself. We had a steak with wine-coffee sauce and steak with orange sauce. Delicious dinner, the meat was juicy and tender. The wine was expensive, like in the rest of Colombia, so we ordered only two glasses.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/salento12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Salento&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are plenty of hostels in Salento. If you are arriving at night, rather book something in advance.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Camelot&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Very nice, clean and quiet hostel located five minutes walk from the main square. The beds are comfortable, but the rooms are mostly without windows. You can use the kitchen, dining room and a terrace. Expect to pay 50.000 COP per night for a double room. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.hostelcamelot.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Camelot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a name=&amp;quot;from-colombia-to-ecuador&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;How to get to Ecuador from Colombia (via Cali and Ipiales)&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Cali&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Departing from Salento you must head to Armenia for 8.000 COP. The bus from Armenia to Cali costs 40.000 COP and it takes about six hours. We stayed in Cali for two nights. Cali is definitely the most dodgy city we have visited in Colombia. Just be careful, because it&amp;#39;s quite dangerous place, as we experienced on our own, when a youngster tried to rob us with a screwdriver in the city center around lunch time. We went out to explore the city center and the local market. We found out that most of the city is dirty and full of beggars.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;One thing what we enjoyed was a salsa club called TinTinDeo. The cocktails were strong and after only three of them we were hammered. We were the only foreigners at that night. If you want to experience an authentic salsa club, we definitely recommend this club. Some of the locals were dancing on a professional level. Yes, you can see and feel that Cali is the salsa capital. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Ipiales&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you are going from Salento to Ecuador, you probably will have to pass through Cali. From Cali head to Ipiales (the bus takes about eight hours and costs 40.000 COP). We recommend to stay there one night. Not just because of having a rest after long journey, but because of the Las Lajas church. We stayed the night in hostel Metropol, which is five minutes walking distance from the bus terminal in Ipiales. Private double room with private bathroom and hot water costs 25.000 COP.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Early morning we took a cab (10.000 COP) to Las Lajas. Tell the driver to stop for the view from above the canyon for pictures. The church is located in the canyon built into the rock. There is really nothing else to do, then to admire the church and the nearby waterfalls. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/salento/las_lajas1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Las Lajas&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Las Lajas&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After a hour you can take a collectivo taxi back to Ipiales bus terminal. At the bus terminal take another collectivo to the border and don&amp;#39;t forget to get a stamp to your passport from the Colombian authorities. After that walk 200m to the Ecuadorian border offices. If you need to, you can exchange the rest of your COP&amp;#39;s for USD with one of the many dealers at the border. The rates were reasonable. We waited for the stamp on Ecuadorian side at least hour and half and then we took a taxi to Tulcan, the closest city. In Tulcan is a bus terminal. We wanted to visit the biggest handcrafts market in Otavalo, so we bought a ticket for 3.75 USD p.p.. There was no bus from Otavalo bus terminal to Quito after 5pm, so we headed to the highway and waited for 15 minutes for a bus driving past to Quito. There are spots along the highway where the buses usually stop to take on passengers. The bus from Otavalo to Quito was 3.5 USD p.p.. It was a very long and exhausting day, but it was worth it.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Medellin</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/medellin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/medellin.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Party in Medellin never stops. We partied every second day till morning. It reminded me of my home city, Prague. We liked the city so much, that we considered the option to move to Medellin.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Paisas&amp;quot; (people from Medellin) are friendly and beautiful people. They will make you feel good in their city. They are aware that Medellin has the stigma of a violent city, controlled by drug cartels from the past, but they don&amp;#39;t like to talk about it. They even don&amp;#39;t want to say the name of Pablo Escobar. Instead our tour guide gave him the nick name Paul Broom, when she was addressing Pablo. It was like in Harry Potter with Lord Voldemort :) The city is now pretty safe and tourists are very welcome. The people of Medellin are happy to see the tourists that they even stop you on the street, shake your hand and ask where you are from. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On our second day, we have visited Parque Arvi, a large natural park on the top of a hill. It used to be a very dangerous place in the past, controlled by guerrillas. It is a getaway from the busy city for locals. That day was a vacation and the park was packed with children and young students. They approached us, gave us high five or told us hi. One girl asked me where I am from. So I answered, but she wasn&amp;#39;t really interested in the answer and she asked me with a smile &amp;quot;Selfie&amp;quot;? :) She wanted a picture with us.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Medellin is the second largest city of Colombia. Surrounded by mountains it was isolated from the world. In 1991, Medellin was the most violent city in the world. In 2013 Medellin was awarded as the most innovative city in the world. Certainly, the construction of the metro, universities and also libraries in the poorest parts of the city helped Medellin to fight the criminality. Nowadays there are still places where you don&amp;#39;t want to go after sunset, like the downtown, but this shouldn&amp;#39;t discourage you from visiting it during day time. Just use your common sense and trust your guts.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;On the first picture below is a sculpture from Fernando Botero, the Bird. In 1995 somebody put a bomb into the Bird and more then thirty people lost their lives and 200 people were wounded. On the other picture is Plaza de Cisneros, what used to be one of the most dangerous places in the city. The city transformed this place by demolishing the old market and building white columns, which shine in the night and a library.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Transport&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can fly or you can go by bus. The bus from Santa Marta took us 19 hours and was 160.000 COP for both of us. Don&amp;#39;t forget that you can bargain at the counters. The initial price was 200.000 COP. Flight ticket would cost 250.000 COP p.p.. The bus was very comfortable with lot of space for legs, adjustable and comfy seats, Wi-fi and a toilet. However it was freezing cold in the bus due to the boosted air condition, very typical in Colombia. Wear a sweater, trousers, jacket and some blanket and you will be fine. The bus was operated by &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.expresobrasilia.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Brasilia company&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Metrocable and Parque Arvi&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take the metro to Acevedo station where you have to change to the cable car. The ticket for the metro is 2.000 COP and is valid also for the cable car until Santo Domingo station. For the cable car from Santo Domingo to Parque Arvi you have to pay 4.500 p.p. each way. It takes you up the hill, over a poor neighborhood. You will see almost the whole city from the cabin.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The park is huge, it has 16.000 hectares. You can enjoy more then 50 miles of hiking trails in a natural forest. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo de Antioquia and Plaza Botero&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This museum is located in the downtown. You can find expositions from Fernando Botero and Luis Caballero. Botero was born in Medellin and is one of the most important artists of Colombia. More then that, there is a hall with modern art of the XX. and XXI. century and a really nice exposition of pre-hispanic ceramics.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Most interesting to us was the temporary exhibition on the ground floor called Piso Piloto. The project was created in collaboration with Barcelona and it is dedicated to the housing issue of both cities. It&amp;#39;s shown in both cities simultaneously. Everyone has the right for a proper home and the truth is, that unfortunately the market is now controlled by brokers and &amp;quot;experts&amp;quot;, who don&amp;#39;t care about people and how they feel in their cities and their homes. The exposition showed interesting projects from students on how to resolve housing issues and make public space more open to people and their interactions. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Fernando Botero donated to Medellin and Bogota dozens of his sculptures and paintings. On Plaza Botero you can admire 23 big statues made by maestro Botero. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Real city walking tour&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We recommend to take the tour on your first days, as you will receive plenty of information and you will visit most of the interesting spots in downtown. The tour is a free tour, however you will be reminded by the guide several times that a tip is more then welcome and that 25.000 COP p.p. would be appropriate. You have to make a reservation on the internet in advance and the tour takes about 3 hours. Comparing this tour to other tours we have done before, this one was the least interesting mainly due to our guide, who treated us like children even calling us gringos and the facts she told us were oversimplified.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Guatape&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The bus leaves from Terminal Norte. Take the metro to Caribe station and go over the bridge to the terminal. It costs 11.500 COP p.p.. The bus drops you off close to the El Piedra (the rock). The bus ride takes around 2 hours. The entrance fee to El Piedra was 11.500 COP. Prepare yourself to walk 750 stairs to the very top. The view is fabulous and reminded us of Plitvicke lakes in Croatia. After El Piedra take a tuk-tuk to the center of Guatape for 10.000 COP. The center is very neat with colorful houses that are called Zocalos. On &amp;quot;plaza quatro esquinas&amp;quot; you can try the most amazing empanadas. An older lady fries them on a corner, with amazing fillings like tender beef and cheese. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape1.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape7.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape8.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape9.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape10.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape11.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape12.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape13.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/guatape14.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Honestly, we spent so much money on parties, that we safe money on food and cooked in our hostel or we ate cheap street food. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Gourmet d&amp;#39;Andres&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They are opened till 16:00 and they serve breakfast and lunch. We haven&amp;#39;t had such high quality menu del dia in South America before. If you had enough of rice, beans and chicken, visit this nice restaurant and sit on the terrace. We ordered steak with potato pie, tuna steak with a fruit sauce and potato pie. The tuna steak was delicious and we loved the juicy piece of beef with red wine sauce. We got also a salad and a dessert. We paid 34.000 COP.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin16.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the backpacker hostels are located in El Poblado and the prices vary from 25.000 COP for a dorm to even 90.000 COP for a double room. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Kiwi hostel&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We didn&amp;#39;t book anything for the first night and we were really tired after a 19 hours bus ride from Santa Marta, that we decided to enjoy a little bit of luxury. We had a double room for 90.000 COP. We really appreciated the large bathroom with hot water and comfortable bed. The hostel has a small pool on the roof and two relaxation areas with hammocks. Breakfast is not included and costs about 6.000 COP, or you can cook your own meal in the kitchen. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Memphis hostel&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is one of the cheapest hostels in Poblado. A double room, costs 60.000 COP. We had our own bathroom and even a terrace. You can use the kitchen and they make coffee every morning for free.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The best party district is El Poblado, with many clubs, restaurants and bars.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Mansion club&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is an electronic music club in the center of El Poblado. Entrance fee was 15.000 COP. It opens on Fridays and Saturdays and the dj&amp;#39;s were playing on real turntables. We really enjoyed the set from the resident djane Juliana. The sound system could use an upgrade though. Insufficient base and lot of distortion. Check the lineup, they have international artists regularly.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/mansionclubmed&amp;quot;&amp;gt;mansion club&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/julianna&amp;quot;&amp;gt;dj julianna&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Parque Lleras&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This park is in the heart of El Poblado. People hangout in the park in the evening hours to share a bottle of rum, beers or micheladas. Michelada is beer mixed with lemon, chili and pepper and a pinch of salt on the cup. Our favorite Colombian beer is Club Colombia. They have three types, blond, red and black. Very popular is Aguardiente, which is very similar to French pastis. We prefer rum and one of the best ones is Ron Medellin. They sell one liter of Ron Medellin in a tetra pack for 34.000 COP.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/medellin/medellin14.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Medellin&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Tayrona</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/tayrona.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/tayrona.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I went for a walk to the palm tree forest behind the beach, trying to find a fresh coconut. As I am walking under the trees I can hear coconuts falling down all the time. I must have picked up at least fifty coconuts to find out that all of them were either empty or rotten. Frustrated as I was, I went deeper to the forest to accomplish my silly mission. After a few minutes walk I came to an clearing with two huge piles of coconuts. On the left coconut shells, on the right heavy, ripe coconuts with liquid inside. I guess the locals have collected them and kept it there. With no one around to ask and to avoid any conflicts with he locals I replaced my empty coconut for the biggest and ripest one I could find from the pile. Perhaps the locals have counted them, who knows :)&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;On the way back to the beach I was trying to throw the coconut against some rocks, smashing it with a pile of wood, hammering against it with a rock and bring Andrea the precious fruit inside. It did not work out. The shell consists of a thick layer of extremely rigid fibers, almost impossible to penetrate without any tools. Arriving at the beach with a bit of a frustration I took another approach. I started to work on the shell like a monkey with a branch and a sharp stone. Little by little I removed the fibers and was able to create an opening. With all my strength I started to remove big chunks of the shell to reveal the coconut inside. It must have taken me 40 minutes at least. Finally there it was in my hand, my own coconut. With a tiny branch I made a whole into the coconut to gain access to the liquid. To our surprise it contained at least 200 ml of fresh coconut water. A nice refreshment after all the hard work. Now it was only a piece of cake to crack the hard shell and to finally have a little snack. It was more then we could eat, so we offered a few pieces to our beach neighbors. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Tayrona national park is located on the northern Caribbean coast of Colombia. Tayrona has the most beautiful beaches that we have ever seen. The Guardian put the Tayrona beaches on the list of &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.theguardian.com/travel/2007/feb/16/beach.top10&amp;quot;&amp;gt;top ten beaches&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of the world.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Tayrona rain forest is home to capybaras (a large rodent), jaguars, monkeys, lizards and many sea species. If you walk quietly in the morning, you can get a glimpse of capybaras searching for food in the bushes, or of the monkeys jumping over the palm trees. The lizards and crabs can be spotted on many places along the paths.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona4.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona5.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona6.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Transport&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take the bus from the market in Santa Marta for 6.000 COP. The ride takes around one hour. On the entrance to Tayrona national park you have to watch an informational video spot and the staff will give you a paper ticket to prove at the service desk, that you watched the video. With that you can go to the queue for the entrance tickets. They will also require an ID card or your passport. The entrance fee is 39.500 COP. We read on the internet, that you are not allowed to enter with plastic bags, which is not true. Neither did they require any vaccination documents. We saw two police officers checking sporadically tourists with large backpacks. Smuggling a small bottle of alcohol would not be too difficult.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After the entrance, take the small bus that will take you further into the National Park. It costs only 3.000 COP p.p and will save you at least 1 hour of boring walk on a paved road. The bus will drop you off close to the walking path. Prepare yourself for a trek of 3 hours in hot and humid conditions. You can rent a horse if you need to for 32.000 COP to the camp Cabo San Juan. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona15.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;What to pack&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We saw tourists with huge backpacks and also a suitcase. For a small fee you can leave your backpacks in your hotel in Santa Marta. We advice you to take a smaller backpack and to pack the following: &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;swimsuit&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;towel&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;headlamp&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;padlock for the locker&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;trousers and sweater for the night&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;t-shirts&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;repellent&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;camera&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;suncream is a must&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;toilet paper&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want to save money you also pack the following:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;5-liters of water per person&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;cans: tuna, sardines, beans etc...&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;bread, biscuits, sweets&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In the camp Cabo San Juan a 0.5l bottle of water costs 3.000 COP and the food is bad and expensive.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Camping&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can choose between two camps, Arrecifes and Cabo San Juan. We stayed in Cabo San Juan. Cabo San Juan is on the beach and it&amp;#39;s allowed to swim there, hwereas staying in Arrecifes you have to walk through the jungle for 15 min to get to Piscina beach, where you can swim safely. In Cabo San Juan you have 3 options:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Hammock 20.000 COP&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Tent 25.000 COP p.p.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cabana 50.000 COP p.p.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sleeping in the hammock is not for everyone. It can get cold in the nights and it&amp;#39;s not very comfortable. The tent has a dirty mattress though it protects you from mosquitoes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Facilities like shower, toilet and a small shop are available. For this prices we would expect a higher quality food and cleanliness. For example our last night only two toilets out of four were available. Four toilets are not sufficient for the capacity of the camp (more then 100 persons) and often we had to wait in a queue. In general the toilets were dirty except for 5 - 6 am in the morning right after the cleaning. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We heard from others, that Arrecifes is much cleaner.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona18.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In San Juan you can get food three times per day. Breakfast 6.000 COP for toast with marmalade or 10.000 COP for eggs, coffee and toast. Lunch and dinner are for 12.000 - 16.000 COP (fish, pork, chicken). Do not even bother to try the coffee or juices, they are watery and tasteless. On the way to Cabo San Juan stop by in Arrecifes for some refreshment, like fresh orange juice from Indians. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona16.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The whole place is an attractions. Incredible beaches and walking paths. The sea is so clean you can see the fish from above the surface. The water has so many colors turquoise, blue, light blue, white. Around the beach is the rain forest with lot of coconut palms, mangroves and rocks. The boulders are huge and flattened by the ocean and wind. They look surreal, like someone has placed them on the beach on purpose.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona17.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tayrona&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Snorkeling&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Along the coastline is a corral reef. Do not snorkel by yourself far away from the beach, the sea is rough with treacherous streams. The warning sings on the coast are a reminder of more then a hundred drowning victims. The ecosystem is so unique and protected, diving is prohibited. On the reception ask for the snorkeling expedition. It takes 2 hours and is absolutely worth the 40.000 COP p.p.. After a safety training with our guide we swam out towards the reef. We saw lot of colorful fish varieties, an octopus, corals, a huge sea snail and a sea snake. If you are lucky you might see manta rays and sea turtles.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona9.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona10.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona11.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona12.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona13.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/tayrona/tayrona14.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Santa Marta</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/santa_marta.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 3 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/santa_marta.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Lying on the Playa Blanca close to Rodadero, reading the first five pages of the Spanish-German text book, a local approached me. Andrea was swimming in the sea and with the little Spanish words that I know I had no clue what this person was talking. My first impression was that it is yet another annoying merchant offering souvenirs or a lunch in the beach restaurants. &amp;quot;Great, leave me alone, I don&amp;#39;t want to buy anything&amp;quot;, were my thoughts :) After several &amp;quot;no gracias&amp;quot; and him standing persistently above me I managed to figure out that he is actually asking me where I am from. He had recognized that I am reading a Spanish-German book and explained to me that he is Colombian born, living in Switzerland for the past 40 years. From that moment the conversation was easy as we switched to German. I felt a bit embarrassed that I rejected him in the first moments, but he understood that I don&amp;#39;t speak Spanish. He was so friendly, that he invited us to his beach tent where he offered us cold beers. Later on, we were invited to have lunch with his family in the nearby restaurant. We spent a lovely afternoon with his nice family laughing about our confusing introduction. A perfect example of Colombian hospitality. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There is not that much special about this city. First place in Colombia that we were not so happy to stay in. The historic center is very small, colonial and a bit similar to Cartagena but definitely not as pretty and neat as Cartagena. We spent four nights here to recover from a food poisoning after Minca. The harbor is located in the bay area next to the beach and close to the historic center. You can see large container ships sailing into the harbor and being un- and on-loaded. Santa Marta is a travel hub as you can depart from here to Tayrona, Minca and Guajirra. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;row&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;carousel col-xs-12 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta2.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta3.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta13.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta14.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Playa Blanca&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Take a bus to Rodadero (1.400 COP) and walk to the right end of the beach. There are several small ships that take you to Playa Blanca (10.000 COP return ticket). The beach is nice and clean and the water is warmer then in Taganga, nevertheless it can&amp;#39;t be compared with Playa Blanca in Cartagena. There are a dozen of restaurants that offer fresh fish. The boats return to Rodadero from 4pm.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Tayrona gold museum&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Compared to the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/blog/2015/bogota.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Museum of Gold&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in Bogota, this one is smaller and is showing similar gold artifacts. You can read on how the artifacts were made, about the techniques, decorations and rituals.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;One part of the Museum is dedicated to the history of Santa Marta and the liberation of slaves. The second floor is dedicated to Simon Bolivar. Probably the most interesting part of this museum is the exposition about indigenous people and their history in Sierra Nevada mountain region. We recommend to pay a visit to this exposition if you plan to go to Minca or Tayrona as you can get lot of information on the indigenous population that still lives in Sierra Nevada. Four indigenous groups live in Sierra Nevada: Kogui, Arhuaco, Wiwa, Arsario and Kankuamo. Social organization, clothing and language vary from group to group, but they share a common view of creation, the Law of Origin: this is a law that is written in every place on the Sierra and contains the principles and rules that govern the material and spiritual lives of the indigenous communities.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The indians chew coca leaves, which they mix with lime as they go about their daily activities on the Sierra. They keep the roasted coca leaves in shoulder bags, while the lime which they extract and put in their mouth with a wooden stick is kept in &amp;quot;poporos&amp;quot; - gourds. For indians, chewing coca leaves and using the gould lime container are fundamental aspects of their relationship with the spiritual world.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The poporo represents their &amp;quot;partner&amp;quot; and in &amp;quot;her&amp;quot; they keep their thoughts and their words, so they do not get carried away by the wind. Because of it vitamins and alkaloid components, coca helps them to remember and recite the myths and chants of &amp;quot;the ancients&amp;quot; during long nocturnal sessions.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Tayrona Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Between the years 200 and 900 of our era, small groups settled around bays and in valleys on Sierra. They engaged in fishing, salt extraction, hunting, metal work... A number of transformations occurred from 900 A.D. onwards, which mark the beginning of the Tayrona Period. Greater complexity in stone construction, such as foundations of houses, pathways, public squares and agricultural terraces, together with the development of a notable hierarchical social structure and concentration of power, and new style of metal work. Food, raw materials, knowledge and manufactured objects were exchanged via social, political, economic and religious circuits which eventually came to link the Sierra with the entire Caribbean and the Eastern Cordillera. In 1501, the European conquistadors were amazed when they saw the Taiyronas, who fought them in violent war that lasted 75 years. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The admission is for free.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Cathedral&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Visit the cathedral and make some pictures. Simon Bolivar was buried here for several years. You can find a memorial plate inside the cathedral.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Cathedral&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Cathedral&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the restaurants are located on carrera 3 and around Parque de los Novios. Some of them are pretty good but pricey. Street food stands are mostly on carrera 5 and around the market. We saw stands with chorrizos and barbecue. The street food did not look very attractive so we skipped it this time.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Barbeque&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Barbeque&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Lulo cafe bar&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This restaurant is in the higher price range. The jugos are super tasty and served in jars. We loved it. We had the jugo combo, where you get the juice of the day, toasted bread, cream cheese with herbs and hummus for 8.000 COP. A fair deal.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The second time we came here, we chose the arepa with cheese, egg, bacon, beans and avocado (12.000 COP). Igor had a wrap with scrambled eggs, tomato, onion, ham, basil and cheese (14.000 COP). Portions are big and we had troubles to finish it. The food was delicious.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.lulocafebar.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lulo cafe bar&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/santa_marta/santa_marta_lulo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Lulo cafe&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Santa Marta - Lulo cafe&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Caribbean wings&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Decent and cheap food. They specialize in chicken wings and offer menu del dia as well. The food is fresh and you can see into the kitchen which is very clean. We went there twice. The prices for menu del dia are from 8.000 COP to 10.000 COP. We had the menu del dia with the chicken wings. They were freshly made, nice and crispy with platanos and rice on the side.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Calle 17 # 2- 59&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Miko&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This rooftop club is located on the left end of the beach in Santa Marta. Dj&amp;#39;s play from Thursday till Saturday. They offer only basic cocktails, but they are very strong and mixed with proper Rum/Vodka. The staff is friendly and the sound system is of high quality and powerful. They played different styles of electronic music. The night we have been there, they were playing house music. The next day when we were passing by, they were playing electro. The club is visited by upscale Colombians mixed with hipster tourists. Not our cup of tea but with the strong drinks and everyone around having fun and dancing we didn&amp;#39;t care about stereotypes and partied on.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.mikobar.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Miko&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Minca</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/minca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/minca.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We went for a walk to the river. On the way there we saw mangoes on the ground, unfortunately most of them were rotten or covered with insects. We did not give up and kept searching. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There is something about eating fresh handpicked fruit, full of taste and juice. It reminds you of the good old times spent in grandmothers garden. The taste of childhood that you can hardly find anywhere else. We felt like little children eating mangoes that we found on the ground directly under the tree. For the first time in our lives we tasted real fresh mangoes. It was a magic experience - sweet, juicy, soft and full of flavor, incomparable to mangoes that you can buy in Europe.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Wandering under the trees, looking for more mangoes a local approached us with a big smile and in his hands he was holding four big, ripe mangoes. Surprised as we were, we almost pulled out money to pay him. Minca people are friendly and forthcoming and they make you feel like home. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Mango&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Mango&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Transportation&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want to relax and run away from hot and busy Santa Marta, go to Minca. It is 40 minutes drive from Santa Marta. Since Minca is in the hills the temperatures are a bit cooler. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;To get there, go to the market in Santa Marta and ask for a car/jeep to Minca. They leave when the car is filled with passengers and they charge 7000 COP. Don&amp;#39;t forget to take enough cash with you, as there is no ATM in Minca.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;About&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Minca is a unique place to live. In the morning you can swim in the sea, for the lunch you can enjoy the rain forest and in the evening you can go for mountain biking in the hills. The mountain peaks of Sierra Nevada are covered with snow.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It&amp;#39;s one of the most beautiful places we&amp;#39;ve seen in Colombia. The flora in Minca has emerald green color and you can hear birds singing and the river flowing. It is a quiet and peaceful place. Sierra Nevada has a huge biodiversity and it is home to toucans, skunks, jaguars, monkeys, caimans and hummingbirds. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Indians consider Sierra Nevada to be the center of the world, or as they call it &amp;quot;pachamama&amp;quot;. It is understandable, the nature is very rich and provided the indigenous people with food for centuries.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Minca is also a well known coffee region with many coffee farms (fincas). Furthermore the cocoa plant grows wildly in Sierra Nevada.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is a small town 650 meters above the sea level. In the past it wasn&amp;#39;t the safest place, since F.A.R.C. (guerrilla group) was controlling this area. The locals told us that the police station was destroyed twice by bombs. The guerrillas were growing marijuana all over the area to finance the organization. The plants are still growing wildly in the forest and you can make out the distinct smell of it. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Nowadays everything is different. Minca is a safe place, visited by tourist every day. Several expats settled down here and build up hotels and restaurants in this little town.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca11.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca12.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca13.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Finca Victoria&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The finca is located 8 km from the village. You can either take a mototaxi (8.000 COP) or you can walk, like we did. It&amp;#39;s a bit difficult hike up the hills, especially in a hot day, but you will be rewarded with amazing views and if you are lucky you will see some animals on the way. We spotted a small armadillo in the bushes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The coffee farm was founded by an English family in 1892. Later on a German family, escaping from Europe because of world war II, took over the finca. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The finca is also home to a small brewery. The water comes from the river, the barley from Germany and hops from Czech Republic. They make two types. Happy tucan is a red ale and happy jaguar is a pilsner.The young German guy that owns the brewery knows how to make good beer. We give it a thumbs up.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The most important business of the finca is coffee production. They will explain you the whole process. From the harvest to cleaning coffee beans and sorting them by quality. At the end of the tour you will taste their coffee and you can buy some coffee. Astonishingly the whole farm is operated by 120 years old machines and a water turbine. They are not thinking about replacing them, the machines still do their job and the generated electricity powers the finca and the surrounding houses. The tour takes 40 minutes, it&amp;#39;s in Spanish and cost 10.000 COP p.p. Recently a group of French people opened a bistro in the finca, where you can buy beer from the local brewery and home made sandwiches.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca9.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca10.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca finca victoria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Cocoa workshop&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Arriving from Santa Marta to Minca, there are two houses on the right side. It&amp;#39;s a cafeteria serving home made cakes and coffee and selling chili sauces and chocolates. We bought a spicy mango-chili salsa. Next to the cafeteria is a small information stand. The guy there told us so many informations about history of Minca and about the local products (honey, salsas, coffee, chocolate products). It was a long but pleasant conversation and he didn&amp;#39;t force us to buy anything. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They are offering one day tours around Minca and Sierra Nevada. They will take you to Finca Victoria, Palo Alto (a view where you can see two highest mountains of Sierra Nevada-Colon and Bolivar), the waterfalls and a chocolate workshop. It costs 55.000 COP p.p. You can go by yourself and visit the places for free. The loop around minca is cca. 20km long. Ask for a map.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.junglejoeminca.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Jungle Joe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is offering bird watching excursions for 25.000 COP p.p.. There is a good chance he will be around since his office is also in the same house. Bird watching is every day from 6 a.m. and finish at 9 a.m. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The cocoa workshop was interesting. Firstly he gave us to try raw chocolate seeds and shells (they have high content of theobromine, a substance making people happy). Then he mixed grounded raw beans with coconut oil (it helps the product to stay solid, as coconut oil has solid form up to 25 degrees) and then we could choose the flavor. From three organic fruit marmalades we choose the blackberry one. Then he mixed everything, grounded the paste, put in a form and let it sit for 15 minutes in a freezer. It was delicious.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca8.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca cocoa workshop&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Pozo Azul&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This waterfall is located cca. one hour walk from Minca, on the way to Finca Victoria. You can swim in crystal clear water, but we have to say that it is very cold.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Pozo Azul&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are a few hostels and hotels in all price categories. We heard that Casa Loma is a really cool place, they have amazing view, but the double rooms are very expensive. We chose Casa Colibri, which is just few minutes from Casa Loma. The owner is French and his wife Venezuelan. They are very friendly and we felt like at home. You can have a rest in a hammock and observe hummingbirds. Their breakfast is good. We had pancakes with fruits. The hostel is very clean and rooms have enough space. We paid around 60.000 COP per night for a double room. The breakfast is 5.000 COP.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are plenty of restaurants to choose from. On the way to Pozo Azul, just 15 minutes walking from Minca, is the restaurant Asador. We didn&amp;#39;t try but we passed by and it looked amazing. The chef was cutting big pieces of meat for the bbq. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Finca Victoria - French bistro&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;They have homemade cakes, we tried their coffee cake. It was very good especially the topping with coffee flavor. We had the club sandwich with chicken, vegetables and egg and a croque-monsieur sandwich with dark bread, bechamel sauce and cheese and salad on the side. The bread is of European type and home made. With two happy tucan beers we paid 30.000 COP. A very pleasant change.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Finca Victoria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Finca Victoria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/minca/minca4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Minca Happy Tucan Beer&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Minca Happy Tucan Beer&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Taganga</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/taganga.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/taganga.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Taganga is a small hippie/fisherman village close to Santa Marta. To get there, catch a collectivo bus anywhere in Santa Marta, it cost 1.400 COP p.p. (0.50 EUR) or take a taxi. It&amp;#39;s just a few minutes drive from the city.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Taganga is a party place. You will meet interesting travelers and hippies and you will probably extend your stay like we did. You plan to come for few days and you might stay for few weeks, like many of the guests we met at the hostels, or as one of the locals explained to us: &amp;quot;You come to Taganga normal, you leave crazy, you come to Taganga crazy, you leave normal&amp;quot;. With the good vibes of this small fishing village you will loose track of time. You can ask around for a volunteering job in the hostels and get a dorm bed and one meal per day in exchange for 6 hours work five days per week. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Transportation&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you go from Cartagena and you want to travel cheap, take the collectivo (small bus that stops anywhere) for 1.800 COP to bus terminal, the ride from the center takes around 1 hour. Once you have arrived at the bus terminal, ignore hustlers and any friendly advisors and go straight to the counters. Ask for a direct bus to Santa Marta. We went with Berlinave for 20.000 COP p.p. (7 EUR) in a bus with AC and a toilet. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Beaches&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The local beach one is not the most picturesque, however there are plenty of restaurants and bars and the water is clean. You can always go to Playa Grande, which is much cleaner. Don&amp;#39;t listen to any advisors and walk there. It will take you just 15 minutes and it&amp;#39;s doable in flip flops. Advantage of going by foot, is the beautiful view over the village and the bay. The path to Playa Grande starts at the very far right of the local beach, just below the hotel that is located on the hill side. At the playa are several restaurants and seats to rent. Swimming at Playa Grande reminded us of swimming in a lake, because the water is so calm and cool. It can be crowded and loud on the weekends, so it&amp;#39; s better to continue your way further around the bay and find &amp;quot;your beach&amp;quot;. Further out are a few small, hidden beaches with only a handful of people. It would be a perfect place, if the hills were not covered with plastic bottles and trash. We think that the people are missing environmental education and we hope that this will change one day. The village is still unspoiled by mass tourism. There are no big hotels or posh restaurants. On the contrary, we hope this won&amp;#39;t change!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/taganga3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you stay during the weekend book a room in advance. There are plenty of cheap hostels, some of them are dirty and half empty and you can&amp;#39;t really socialize. If you are a party animal and you don&amp;#39;t mind to be nonstop with people, go to the hostel Nirvana. They have only dormitories with 15 bunk beds, a swimming pool in the courtyard. Most of the guests are in their twenties.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;If you want a nice, cozy and quiet place, go to the Garden House hostel or the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.lacasadefelipe.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;San Felipe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; hostel. We stayed at San Felipe. It&amp;#39;s a bit more expensive for Taganga, 65.000 COP (22.60 EUR) per night for a double room, but it is worth it. You have your own bathroom with a toilet, fan and a safe. It&amp;#39;s located at the foot of a hill. It has a &amp;quot;mirador&amp;quot;, a terrace with a view over the see, where you can relax in hammocks. You can use a kitchen and a lounge with TV as well. The breakfast cost from 4.000 COP to 7.000 COP. We loved their coffee. This was by far the cleanest Hotel on our trip in Colombia.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We also stayed three nights in Alquimista hostal, which is one of the cheapest in the village. They have dorms in the main building, where you can also find a patio with kitchen, bar, TV and couches. The price of a dorm bed with AC is 18.000 COP (6.30 EUR) per night, but we recommend you to find a buddy and rent a double room. The double rooms (3 in total) are located in another building, just 50 meters from the main one, so it&amp;#39;s more quiet. It costs 39.000 COP (13.50 EUR) per night, so there is almost no difference in the price. There is a lounge, terrace, kitchen and a bathroom. Breakfast is included.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;The drinks on the bar are very cheap. Carlos, the manager, employs young volunteers who speak English. We had a lot of fun here and we were coming back even when we were staying in San Felipe.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Street food is available at the entire beach promenade. You can get arepas, tortillas or sausages and fresh juices and cocktails. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Dunkarinka&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The best fish we&amp;#39;ve had in Colombia. Go for menu del dia and ask what fish they have on menu. We were in Colombia in the season of mojarra, which is a good average fish. For a change we put a little bit more money and we ordered the sierra fish. It&amp;#39;s a big fish with enough meat for two people. Like always it came with coconut rice, salad and a fish soup and we paid 15.000 COP (5,20 EUR) p.p. They will also ask you how you want it to be prepared. We tried fried and barbecued fish before, so this time we ordered it cooked in a vegetable salsa. The salsa was delicious, the fish juicy, soft like butter and not greasy like when fried.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/fish_sierra1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/taganga/fish_sierra2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Taganga&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Don&amp;#39;t go to &amp;quot;Barracuda&amp;quot;, terrible service and the worst food what we&amp;#39;ve had here. &amp;quot;Yammy Yammy&amp;quot; wasn&amp;#39;t bad and it&amp;#39;s cheap, we enjoyed their juices.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Nightlife&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The gringo discos by the beach playing &amp;quot;international music&amp;quot; (Rihanna, David Guetta, Pit bull and other commercial crap). If you ask around, you can find nice parties, especially on the weekends. We were in the Compass bar, it&amp;#39;s located up the hill nearby the football playground. It&amp;#39;s a garden bar and sometimes they have live music. We were there for a concert of cumbia music, the band is called Kumbia Kuatika. The band is originally from Argentina. They play traditional Peruvian cumbia. Their repertoire includes big classics of Peruvian and Colombian cumbia or &amp;quot;chicha&amp;quot; but mostly they play their own songs. The music is very live and temper and that&amp;#39;s what we like.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Kumbia Kuatika - &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/kumbia.kuatika&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Facebook&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; | &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IEgbCgCr864&amp;quot;&amp;gt;YouTube&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will be offered a variety of substances in Taganga. It&amp;#39;s your choice, but what we heard is not reasonable to walk around with it in the night. The everywhere present police can stop and frisk you and then escort you to the ATM...&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cartagena</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/cartagena.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 8 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/cartagena.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/cartagena_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Playa Blanca&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There are several ways how to get to Playa Blanca. You can either buy a tour from guides on the street, in your hostel or you can get there on your own with a bus and a boat. We read on the internet that you can try to find a spot on a boat close to Mercado Bazurto and you don&amp;#39;t have to pay 12.000 COP (4.20 EUR) park fee. Afterwards we met other travelers, who confirmed that it is possible to get to Playa Blanca on your own for 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR) one way p.p. and sleep in a hammock for 20.000 COP (7 EUR) per night.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We chose the easy way and booked a tour for 85.000 COP (29.50 EUR) p.p. including transportation and accommodation for one night on Playa Blanca. The chartered bus took us to a small harbor, where a boat was waiting for us. The ride with the boat takes around 1 hour. We stayed at &amp;quot;Hostal Playa Blanca&amp;quot; in a small hut-like room (cabana). All hostels are located directly on the beach 10m max from the sea. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The beach is amazing, the sand is almost white and the water warm and turquoise. The locals stay on one side of the beach which is very crowded. Most of the hostels are on the other side of the beach where it is more quiet and not that busy. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will find various restaurants and stands with food on Playa Blanca. We recommend to go to the part where the locals are staying and where you can order a plate with fresh fish for 10.000 - 12.000 COP (3.50 - 4.20 EUR). In the evening the prices can double. The salesmen with the stalls offer overpriced shrimps or langustas (from august), but you can always bargain with them. We wanted a portion of shrimps and the merchant started with 30.000 COP. We were able to negotiate it down to 15.000 COP (5.20 EUR). Same goes for cocktails. They can prepare fancy cocktails for you served in a pineapple or coconut. We bargained the price for two pineapple piña coladas to 23.000 COP (8 EUR), 7.000 COP less then the initial price. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can rent a jet ski for 30.000 COP (10.50 EUR) per 15 minutes. We borrowed snorkels, but we did not see anything interesting on the sea bed.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/playa_blanca1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/playa_blanca2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Playa Blanca&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;City center&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The historic center is small and is surrounded by city walls. The architecture is similar to southern cities in Spain. The buildings have nice, refreshing patios and the balconies are covered with flowers. Just take a camera and get lost for few hours. This district is posh and bit more expensive then the rest of the city. You can find very expensive restaurants, boutique hotels and jewelery shops, specialized in emeralds. We saw nice design shops selling original swimsuits, shoes and hand made jewelery. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you want to save money you can eat on the street or find restaurants that offer menu del dia and live in a hostel at district Getsemani. Unfortunately we didn&amp;#39;t have enough time to explore Getsemani. It&amp;#39;s covered with street art, we saw pieces from Bogotas artist DjLu on Calle de la Sierpe. Visit Plaza de la Trinidad in the evening hours, where locals hang out. Have some fresh arepas or hamburgers from the stalls. Afterwards you can go to one of the many bars, they have happy hours for cocktails and special offers, like 2 for 20.000 COP (7 EUR). We heard that on Calle Arsenal has several cool clubs.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/cartagena_center1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/cartagena_center2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Cartagena Center&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Naval museum&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It&amp;#39;s located in the historic center and the admission is 8.000 COP (2.80 EUR) p.p.. The museum has two large wings. The lower one is dedicated to the naval history of Colombia and especially Cartagena de Indias. You could spend hours reading the information boards, few of them are in English. The second wing is dedicated to the modern Colombian navy. We had lot of fun in a model of submarine command bridge, pushing buttons, playing with periscope and shooting enemy ships. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.museonavaldelcaribe.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.museonavaldelcaribe.com/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Try some fresh fish or sea food you are on the coast after all. When we were there in July it was the season for Mujarra, a very tasty fish. Menu del dia will set you back 10.000-15.000 COP. In the evening the street sellers offer classic arepa con queso (grilled corn paddy filled with cheese) for 1.000 COP (0.35 EUR). Besides that they offer meat sticks, potatoes filled with meat or fried cheese rolls. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/food1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Mujarra Fish&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Mujarra Fish&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Restaurante Atahualpa&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We chose the menu with fish for 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR). The fish soup was very good with whole pieces of meat and yuka, sprinkled with cilantro leaves and lime juice. The main course consists of fish, rice, beans in a sauce and pickled vegetables. The portions were big. We also recommend to try their lulu juice. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/cartagena/food2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Food&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Food&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Bogota</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/bogota.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/bogota.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/bogota_header.jpg&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Attractions&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo Botero&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.banrepcultural.org/museo-botero&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.banrepcultural.org/museo-botero&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Most of the items in this museum were donated by the famous Colombian artist Fernando Botero. This museum is for free and it also houses a numismatic museum. Botero has a very distinct style and you might find that he is obsessed with painting fat people. Botero said about his figures, “What I say is that they are not fat, but voluminous. If I make a fruit, a landscape, an animal, a man, anything, it is a deformation to exalt volume. So I do not see them as fat, but as voluminous. Fat can also be Michelangelo, Masaccio or all Florentine art that is voluminous.”&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Besides Boteros paintings and sculptures you can admire paintings from Picasso, Gustav Klimt, Max Ernst, Joan Miro, Salvador Dalí and many more. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/botero_horse.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Boteros Horse&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Botero Horse&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/botero_monalisa.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Botero Monalisa&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Boteros Monalisa&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/joan_miro.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Joan Miro&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Joan Miro&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Museo del oro (Museum of gold)&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is the biggest museum of gold in South America. It displays thousands of gold, silver and coper artifacts from the ancient indian history. Not only can you admire the artifacts but the exhibition tells a story on how the objects were made and how they were used in ceremonies and what spiritual role they played in the life of the ancient people.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can read about priests and shamans who identified them selfs with bats, evoked this animal habits in they own, they lived in dark temples, worked at night and flew when they were in transes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Yopo, a powerful hallucinogen that was extracted from the Anadenanthera tree, came from the Eastern Plains. It was inhaled using a small spoon or bird bone from trays with animals depicted on them that conjured up images of the transformations that were experienced.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The entry fee is only 3.000 COP (1 EUR)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/museo_del_oro.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Museo del oro&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Museo del oro - trays and bones for snorting&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Monserrate&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Monserrate is the hill above Candelaria and the city center. You can either access it by walking up the very steep steps (at least 60 min. hard climbing) or you can go for the easier option and take the cable car. The costs for the cable car is 8.500 COP (3 EUR) one way. You can return walking (30 min.). The return ticket is 17.000 COP (6 EUR). On the top of the hill are a monastery, small botanic garden and a market with hand crafted products and food. The view of the city is spectacular.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;National Museum&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is admission free and currently undergoing a reconstruction. Most of the descriptions and informations are written only in Spanish. However there is one remarkable exhibition room with marvelous paintings and projections which does not require any explanations. We have never before seen an exhibition room like this. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/national_museum.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;National Museum&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;National Museum&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Graffiti tour&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Meeting point is at Plaza de Periodistas at 10am or 2pm nearby the statue of Simon Bolivar. The tour takes around 2.5 hours and goes through La Candeleria district and finishes in downtown. Be prepared to hear tons of informations not only on the graffiti and the artists but also on social and economic issues of Bogota. Other then that you will get tips on restaurants, bars, alternative shops and galleries. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Street art in Bogota is nowadays well established and recognized by its citizens, landlords and shop owners. Street art is present everywhere but especially in Candelaria, where artists can even work by daylight in safe zones. Some landlords choose to commission international artists to avoid having their facade being tagged. Once the facade is covered with a piece, other artists respect it and they don&amp;#39;t paint over it. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will see pieces from Guecho, Rodez, Crisp, Likme, APC, Bastardia, DjLu,&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Even though the tour is free a tip of 20.000 - 30.000 COP (7 - 10 EUR) is appropriate.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art - La Candelaria&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art - La Candelaria&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art - Toxicomano&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art - Toxicomano&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/street_art4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Street art&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Where to stay&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Candelaria&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the historic center of Bogota. Some of the colonial houses are dating back 500 years. There are no two identical buildings. You will find many design shops, cheap hostels, restaurants and bars over there. Most of the historic monuments (Plaza Bolivar, Museo Botero, Monserrate ... ) are in walking distance.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Several universities are located in the Candelaria district. Many students and young people come to Plaza de Quevedo to enjoy street performances (mostly live music) and drinks (chicha, aquardiente or beer). This is definitely one of the best hot spots to meet with locals and have a drink.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We stayed in Casa Quevedo that is located at the Plaza de Quevedo and the party is right outside the door. Prices are around 50.000 COP (17 EUR) for a double room per night, breakfast included (eggs, bread, coffee). The 2nd floor has only two toilets which were not always clean.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Typical dishes from Bogota are Bandeja Paisa, which consists of meat, sausage, rice and beans and Aijaco, which is a soup with corn, yucca, potatoes and meat. If you are into sweats Columbia has a lot to offer. You can try pastry and cakes from tamarind, dulce de leche (caramelized condensed milk) and different types of fruit.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;When in Bogota try Chicha drink. It is fermented corn alcohol beverage, very sweet and sour. From Plaza Quevedo leads a narrow street in which every pub and bar serves this drink in a cup made out of totumo. Totumo is a typical plant for Colombia. Be warned that the portion is really big and not everyone likes the taste.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/bogota/food1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Aijaco Soup&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Aijaco Soup&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Dos Gatos y Simone&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;It is a cozy restaurant and the food is good. It is easy to miss, because it is all painted with graffiti from the outside. We chose estofado, which is meat with rice, some veggies, guacamole and salsa. The meat was tender and juicy, the sauce and the guacamole were nicely seasoned and tasty. One meal was with 20.000 COP (7 EUR) a bit pricey for Bogota.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Tao Calentao&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The biggest problem with this place is to find it. It&amp;#39;s hidden in small alley close to Universidad de Los Andes. Ask the students around they will point you in in the right direction. Calentao is a typical Colombian dish from rice, meat, beans and vegetables. You can select all ingredients yourself, or choose from one of the four versions on the menu (Argentinian, Thai, Mexican, Italian ). This is a bistro style and the food is prepared in front of you. Prices are reasonable and the portions are huge. We had troubles to finish our meals. We paid 28.000 COP (9.70 EUR) for two meals with lemonade.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Plaza de Mercado de Paloquemao&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The market is far from the center. Getting there on foot is possible, but don&amp;#39;t draw too much attention onto yourself as you are walking through some shady neighborhoods. It&amp;#39;s located on the corner of Carrera 28 and Calle 19 in front of a modern shopping center. The market offers a large selection of fruits, vegetables and herbs. Inside the market you will find several stands with authentic, home made cuisine. We had two soups, two main dishes (large portion of fried and barbecued chicken leg, lentils, platano and arepa) and lemonade. Altogether we paid only 10.000 COP (3.50 EUR). The portions were big and the locals were super friendly to us. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>http://www.viabohemia.net/blog/2015/berlin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2015/berlin.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;When one of our best friends moved to Berlin, we knew that sooner or later we will come to visit him. Andrea has never been to Berlin before. She loves techno music, art and good food, so for her Berlin was a must-do-trip. Berlin is incredibly cheap, provided you eat on the street, drink beer (not cocktails) and you stay in a hostel rather then a hotel. In that case you can experience Berlin on a budget. Berlin offers lot of fun activities and attractions. To visit all of the techno clubs in Berlin, would be our favorite choice. However, if you are not into electronic music, Berlin offers lot of exhibitions, galleries, museums, concerts and a free street art tour, which we highly recommend. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can find more information here:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.visitberlin.de/en/see/museums-art/art&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.visitberlin.de/en/see/museums-art/art&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.exberliner.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.exberliner.com/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Free street art tour&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you like street art, join the alternative Berlin tour. Our guide Carl from Scotland who really loves this city and obviously knows a lot about the history and its underground subcultures. The tour started in the center, district Mitte. He showed us pieces from El Bocho, Sobre, Mr. Six and others. Then we moved on to the most &amp;quot;alternative&amp;quot; district, Kreuzberg. Since the tour we have looked at the city with different eyes, looking for art everywhere. We really appreciated that we were a small group about ten people and we didn&amp;#39;t disturb people around, because every time we kept distance. We also got tips about good restaurants and clubs where to go. This was a free tour and the three hours passed quickly, however we were very satisfied and left a tip and so did the rest of our group. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin1.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin2.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin3.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Optional title&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;East Side Gallery&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin4.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin5.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the longest open air gallery in the world with the most bitter history. That wall used to divide the city in two parts, the western and the eastern communist world. Many people died trying to cross it. Some of those who managed to flee had to leave rest of their families behind. It is the longest piece of the original Berlin wall with 101 murals from artists from all over the world and of course it is for free. It&amp;#39;s located in Mühlenstraße in Berlin Friedrichshain. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.eastsidegallery-berlin.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;East Side Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Techno clubs&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We have visited three clubs in two days, but you can go nonstop from Friday till Monday and there are so many of them that you won&amp;#39;t know what to choose. Of course you can use &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Residentadvisor&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; but even better is to ask the locals for the most recent hot spots, because some of them are very touristy and that&amp;#39;s not the best you can get. You can try to get to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.berghain.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Berghain&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, but count on a 2 hours queue and strong possibility that the bouncers wont let you in. Don&amp;#39;t go in large groups, and try to be of mixed gender, dressed preferably in dark clothes. Don&amp;#39;t draw too much attention on you, by speaking loudly or by being obviously drunk. Very popular and good techno clubs in the city are &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://aboutparty.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;://about blank&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.sisyphos-berlin.net/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sysiphos&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.kitkatclub.org/Home/Club/Index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Kitkat&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.water-gate.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Watergate&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We started on Saturday midnight in &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://tresorberlin.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tresor&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and we were a bit too early, because the club was almost empty. On the other hand it was easy and quick to get in because there was no queue. Tresor is totally worth to see! Its dark, very charismatic and industrial. The void audio sound systems on both stages rocks.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Later that night we moved on to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://griessmuehle.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Griessmuehle&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, which was probably one of our best techno events ever. We stayed only for three hours but it was a total blast. The club was hosting dj&amp;#39;s and producers from the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/lobster-theremin&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lobster Theremin&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; label. We are not sure if it was just because we were lucky to listen to such high quality techno music or if the club is organizing high class events like this every week. It was simply amazing. The interior and exterior is supporting this raw dirty techno atmosphere. There were no lights, no strobos on the main stage, just a bit of light from the bar which intensified the atmosphere. Be careful on the toilets which are the worst we have ever seen:) You can also chill out in the sun outside by the river.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Sunday night all major clubs play mostly minimal techno or housy music. Since we are not the biggest fans of that, we decided to go to the club R19, which turned out to be a mistake. Please don&amp;#39;t go there! Just if you like bad music, cyber techno or psytrance (I think it&amp;#39;s the same) and you can deal with weird people. Anyway it was an experience.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin6.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Alt text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Tresor&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/mixmag-1/imprint-100-lobster-theremin-label-mix-by-asquith&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lobster Theremin set&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Food&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.monsieurvuong.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Monsieur Vuong&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Alte Schoenhauser Str. 46&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Super fast service and good quality food. The food came five minutes after we have ordered. You can choose from a daily menu or order a la carte and the prices are more then reasonable, from 5-10 EUR. We ordered chicken with mango and minced meat rolls with noodles and fresh vegetables. Both dishes and the home made lemonade were super fresh. The Pho soup was ok, we have had better though. The service was efficient and nice. For two daily menu dishes, the pho soup and two home made lemonades we paid 33 EUR.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.curry36.de/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Curry 36&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Mehringdamm 36 und Bahnhof Zoologischer Garten&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;They claim that it is the best curry wurst in the city, The sauce was obviously home made and Andrea chose an organic sausage which was juicy and soft. For a middle sized sausage with fries we paid 3,50 EUR. Nice and cheap lunch. 10 meters from Curry 36 is probably one of the best places to eat kebab but prepare yourself to wait for at least 30 minutes, it is called Mustafa. We were standing by watching people getting their kebabs and they looked awesome, very fresh and in big sizes.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.burgermeister.berlin/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Burgermeister&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, Oberbaumstrasse 8&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;This is very nice and cheap fast food in the Kreuzberg district. I would appreciate a bigger portion of meat, but what can you ask for if you pay 4 EUR for a burger. The bun was delicious and obviously home made, the fries were also very good. Waiting in the queue, ordering and preparation time, all together it took max 20 minutes to get our food.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/berlin7.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Burger from Burgermeister&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Burger from Burgermeister&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;What movies to watch and what to listen before (or while) you go&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Baader_Meinhof_Complex&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Baader Meinhof Complex (2008)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. is a 2008 German film by Uli Edel. Written and produced by Bernd Eichinger, it stars Moritz Bleibtreu, Martina Gedeck, and Johanna Wokalek. The film is based on the 1985 German best selling non-fiction book of the same name by Stefan Aust. It retells the story of the early years of the West German far-left militant group the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rote_Armee_Fraktion&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Rote Armee Fraktion&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (Red Army Faction, or RAF) from 1967 to 1977. The film was nominated for Best Foreign Language Film at the 81st Academy Awards. It was also nominated for the Golden Globe in the Best Foreign Language Film category.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lives_of_Others&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Lives of Others&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (German: Das Leben der Anderen) is a 2006 German drama film, marking the feature film debut of filmmaker Florian Henckel von Donnersmarck, about the monitoring of East Berlin by agents of the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stasi&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stasi&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Germany&amp;quot;&amp;gt;GDR&amp;#39;s&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; secret police. It stars Ulrich Mühe (who died within a year of the film&amp;#39;s release) as Stasi Captain Gerd Wiesler, Ulrich Tukur as his superior Anton Grubitz, Sebastian Koch as the playwright Georg Dreyman, and Martina Gedeck as Dreyman&amp;#39;s lover, a prominent actress named Christa-Maria Sieland. The film was released in Germany on 23 March 2006. At the same time, the screenplay was published by Suhrkamp Verlag. The Lives of Others won the 2006 Academy Award for Best Foreign Language Film. The film had earlier won seven Deutscher Filmpreis awards—including those for best film, best director, best screenplay, best actor, and best supporting actor—after setting a new record with 11 nominations. It was nominated for Best Foreign Language Film at the 64th Golden Globe Awards.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Run_Lola_Run&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Run Lola Run&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (German: Lola rennt, literally &amp;quot;Lola runs&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Lola is running&amp;quot;) is a 1998 German thriller film written and directed by Tom Tykwer and starring Franka Potente as Lola and Moritz Bleibtreu as Manni. The story follows a woman who needs to obtain 100,000 Deutsche Mark in twenty minutes to save her boyfriend&amp;#39;s life. The film&amp;#39;s three scenarios are reminiscent of the 1981 Krzysztof Kieślowski film Blind Chance; following Kieślowski&amp;#39;s death.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Good Bye, Lenin![1] is a 2003 German tragicomedy film. Directed by Wolfgang Becker, the cast includes Daniel Brühl, Katrin Saß, Chulpan Khamatova, and Maria Simon. Most scenes were shot at the Karl-Marx-Allee in Berlin and around Plattenbauten near Alexanderplatz.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christiane_F._–_We_Children_from_Bahnhof_Zoo&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Christiane F. – Wir Kinder vom Bahnhof Zoo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is a 1981 German film directed by Ulrich Edel that portrays the drug scene in West Berlin in the 1970s, based on the non-fiction book of the same name written following tape recordings of teenage girl Christiane F. The movie immediately acquired cult status (which it still retains today) and features David Bowie as both himself and the soundtrack composer, which gave the movie a commercial boost. Both the movie and the book acquired cult status in Europe immediately after release, raising awareness of heroin addiction. The popularity of the movie was greatly boosted by David Bowie&amp;#39;s participation as both himself (portrayed giving a concert early in the movie) and as the main contributor to the soundtrack. Bowie&amp;#39;s music from his albums made in Berlin during 1976-77 is heavily featured throughout the picture, and as he was at the very peak of his popularity during the late 1970s-early 1980s, his presence helped boost the film&amp;#39;s commercial success.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/baader_meinhof_complex.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Baeder Meinhof Komplex&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/img/berlin/good_bye_lenin.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Baeder Meinhof Komplex&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;East Side Gallery&amp;quot;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ben Klock&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/benklock&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/benklock&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/ben-klock&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/ben-klock&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Rødhåd&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/rodhad&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/rodhad&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/rodhad&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/rodhad&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Marcel Dettman&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/marceldettmann&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/marceldettmann&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/marceldettmann&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/marceldettmann&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Sven Vath&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/svenvath&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/svenvath&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/hightension1053/sven-vath-live-time-warp-2015-mannheim-germany-06-04-2015&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/hightension1053/sven-vath-live-time-warp-2015-mannheim-germany-06-04-2015&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Motor city drum ensemble&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/mcde&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/mcde&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/platform/motor-city-drum-ensemble-dekmantel&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/platform/motor-city-drum-ensemble-dekmantel&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Chris Liebing&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrisliebing&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrisliebing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/chris-liebing&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/chris-liebing&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Pan Pot&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/pan-pot&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/pan-pot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/pan-pot&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/pan-pot&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ostgut ton&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/record-label.aspx?id=803&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/record-label.aspx?id=803&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/ostgutton-official&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/ostgutton-official&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Cassy&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/cassy&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/cassy&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://soundcloud.com/cassy-official-1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;https://soundcloud.com/cassy-official-1&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>	  
    </item>

  </channel> 
</rss>
